const quiz = [
  
  {
    "id": 1,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The danger of volcanoes ……….. not to be taken lightly.",
    "options": ["must", "might", "has", "have"],
    "answer": "must"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Ramesh ……… here for the last seven years.",
    "options": ["worked", "is working", "has worked", "works"],
    "answer": "has worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Supply the correct tag for the following statement. *Let us go,* ………..",
    "options": ["shall we?", "will we?", "do we?", "don't we?"],
    "answer": "shall we?"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Two ladies had ……… hand bags stolen at the Kathmandu Mall.",
    "options": ["its", "her", "their", "they"],
    "answer": "their"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "They are as lucky as ………..",
    "options": ["we", "our", "ourselves", "us"],
    "answer": "us"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Sincere people abide ……… their promise.",
    "options": ["by", "of", "at", "on"],
    "answer": "by"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The new manager will ……… his position on August 30.",
    "options": ["take off", "take out", "take over", "take after"],
    "answer": "take over"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct alternative for underlined phrase in the given sentence. He got a Lion's share of the profits.",
    "options": ["no share at all", "greater share of a things", "very small part", "little profit"],
    "answer": "greater share of a things"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "There is someone in the room ……….. I certainly heard a great noise.",
    "options": ["and", "but", "for", "so"],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Neither of them ……… a problem.",
    "options": ["anticipate", "anticipates", "have anticipated", "are anticipating"],
    "answer": "anticipates"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct passive voice for the following sentence. We celebrate Democracy Day on Falgun seven.",
    "options": [
      "Democracy Day is celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day was celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day has been celebrated on Falgun seven by us.",
      "Democracy Day had been celebrated on Falgun seven by us."
    ],
    "answer": "Democracy Day is celebrated on Falgun seven by us."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "She is ……….. obedient student.",
    "options": ["an", "a", "the", "none of the above"],
    "answer": "an"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct answer from among the given options. I don't think I ……… be able to go.",
    "options": ["will", "should", "can", "could"],
    "answer": "will"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct single word for the group of words given below. That which cannot be divided.",
    "options": ["indelible", "indivisible", "insoluble", "indefensible"],
    "answer": "indivisible"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words is an abstract noun?",
    "options": ["desk", "fear", "class", "needle"],
    "answer": "fear"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words does not have a suffix?",
    "options": ["helpless", "goodness", "fearless", "courage"],
    "answer": "courage"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The opposite meaning of 'accepted' is,",
    "options": ["liked", "noted", "provided", "rejected"],
    "answer": "rejected"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the word nearest in meaning to 'emulate'.",
    "options": ["Imitate", "Deny", "Discuss", "Reject"],
    "answer": "Imitate"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct synonym for the underlined word in the following sentence. Raman is a versatile boy.",
    "options": ["bad", "clumsy", "gifted", "lazy"],
    "answer": "gifted"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct antonym for 'segregation'.",
    "options": ["appreciation", "integration", "cohesion", "co-ordination"],
    "answer": "integration"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Fill in the gap with the correct word from among the given options. The price of consumer goods ……… increasing.",
    "options": ["are", "is", "were", "has been"],
    "answer": "is"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following sentences is incorrect in terms of subject verb agreement?",
    "options": [
      "Each of the women owns her home.",
      "All of the women own their own homes.",
      "Here are two wrenches and a hammer.",
      "Here is a hammer and two wrenches."
    ],
    "answer": "Here is a hammer and two wrenches."
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following sentences has the correct use of comma (;)?",
    "options": [
      "June 27, 2018, is a day I will never forget.",
      "Some people who go to school, enjoy the social life.",
      "He was late for dinner, we decided to eat without him.",
      "We were glad to see him, because he had brought gifts."
    ],
    "answer": "June 27, 2018, is a day I will never forget."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the part participate of the verb quit.",
    "options": ["quited", "quit", "quitting", "has quit"],
    "answer": "quit"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct alternative from among the given options. *We spent a ...... evening together.*",
    "options": ["quite", "quit", "quiet", "quitter"],
    "answer": "quiet"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following words needs capitalization?",
    "options": ["winter", "ocean", "jewish", "university"],
    "answer": "jewish"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the correct preposition from among the given options. *He is occurred ...... cheating.*",
    "options": ["for", "of", "on", "in"],
    "answer": "of"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct alternative to fill in the gap in the following sentence. *He is coming here ...... six o'clock.*",
    "options": ["upon", "on", "at", "to"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the correct meaning of the idiom in, *In the good book of*",
    "options": [
      "enjoying a pleasant moment.",
      "enjoying a favour of someone.",
      "possessing a good book for reading.",
      "purchasing a good book."
    ],
    "answer": "enjoying a favour of someone."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Fill in the gap in the following sentence from among the given options. *I am ...... tired to go any further.*",
    "options": ["to", "too", "so", "not"],
    "answer": "too"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which is the correct indirect speech for the direct speech given below? *Hari says, \"I am very happy\".*",
    "options": [
      "Hari says he is very happy.",
      "Hari says he was very happy.",
      "Hari said he is very happy.",
      "Hari said he was very happy."
    ],
    "answer": "Hari says he is very happy."
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Select the interrogative sentence from the given options below.",
    "options": [
      "Shall I see you tomorrow?",
      "He has studied English for a long time.",
      "They won't believe you.",
      "It will be dark soon."
    ],
    "answer": "Shall I see you tomorrow?"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Put the correct verb form in the gap below. *I ...... told you earlier if I had known.*",
    "options": ["would", "would have", "had", "should"],
    "answer": "would have"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Choose the right pronoun from the given alternatives in the following sentence. *If everybody does ...... part, the game should go smoothly.*",
    "options": ["his", "her", "his or her", "their"],
    "answer": "his or her"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following word is an adverb?",
    "options": ["good", "bad", "well", "melt"],
    "answer": "well"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is the same in meaning as in the word 'obliterate' used in the passage?",
    "options": ["Wipe out", "Wipe off", "Very Literate", "Remove"],
    "answer": "Wipe out"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is term regarding the reasons for progress in genetic engineering?",
    "options": [
      "Poor countries need genetic information.",
      "It has become popular subject.",
      "Economically and scientifically advanced countries can provide infrastructure for such research.",
      "Human beings are interrelated in hereditary."
    ],
    "answer": "Economically and scientifically advanced countries can provide infrastructure for such research."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "According to the passage the question of abortion is,",
    "options": ["hotly debated", "ignored", "unanswered", "undecided"],
    "answer": "hotly debated"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about the genetic engineering?",
    "options": [
      "Acquired ability to detect disorder in unborn babies.",
      "Possibility of abuse.",
      "Increased tendency to manipulate gene cells.",
      "Acquired ability to manipulate tissue cells."
    ],
    "answer": "Increased tendency to manipulate gene cells."
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "According to the author of the passage, the present state of knowledge about heredity has made geneticists.",
    "options": ["reckless", "optimistic", "introspective", "arrogant"],
    "answer": "optimistic"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A number is divided by 10 gives a remainder 7. If the same number is divided by 5, then what will be the remainder?",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following value of 'n' gives the negative result on \( n^2 - 15 \)?",
    "options": ["7", "5", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 'n' is an integer, then which one of the following expression must be even?",
    "options": ["n(n + 1)", "n^2 + 1", "n(n + 2)", "n(n + 4)"],
    "answer": "n(n + 1)"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the sum of first five prime numbers?",
    "options": ["18", "25", "26", "28"],
    "answer": "28"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If you save 1 paisa today, 2 paisa next day, 4 paisa the succeeding day and so on, then what is the total saving on the week?",
    "options": ["127 paisa", "64 paisa", "256 paisa", "128 paisa"],
    "answer": "127 paisa"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of \(\\square \\square \\square \\square\) ? \[ n \\square 10 \]",
    "options": ["0", "-1", "1", "10"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 6 is subtracted from the cube of a number and the result is 21, then what is the value of that number?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the product of two consecutive even number is 288, then what are these numbers from following?",
    "options": ["14, 12", "14, 16", "16, 18", "22, 24"],
    "answer": "16, 18"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The total of ages of A and B is 3:5, if B is 8 years elder to A, then what is the age of the A?",
    "options": ["12 yrs.", "15 yrs.", "18 yrs.", "21 yrs."],
    "answer": "12 yrs."
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the root of the equation \(x^2 - 6x + c = 0\) is 3, then what is the value of c?",
    "options": ["3", "6", "8", "9"],
    "answer": "9"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for the roots of the equation \(x^2 - 8x + 16 = 0\)?",
    "options": ["imaginary & unequal", "rational & unequal", "real & equal", "real & unequal"],
    "answer": "real & equal"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the matrix is of order 5 x 3, then how many elements will be single column?",
    "options": ["5", "3", "4", "15"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(x - 5 = 1\), then what is the value of \(x + 7\)?",
    "options": ["5", "7", "8", "13"],
    "answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(5x + 13 = 31\), what is the value of \(\\square 5x \\square 31 \\square\) ?",
    "options": ["5", "6", "7", "8"],
    "answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the correct value of . \[5 \\cdot \\square 5 \\cdot 55.\]",
    "options": ["5^3", "5", "5^4", "4"],
    "answer": "5^4"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(a^x = b, b^y = c\) and \(c^z = a\), then what is the value of \(xyz\)?",
    "options": ["c", "a", "b", "1"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(6p + 6q = 36\), then what is the average value of a and b?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If \(p + q = r\), then what is the average value of p, q and r?",
    "options": ["p", "q", "r", "(p+q+r)/3"],
    "answer": "(p+q+r)/3"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the slope of the line whose equation is \( 2x - 4y = 9? \)",
    "options": ["1", "\( \\frac{1}{2} \)", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "\( \\frac{1}{2} \)"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is correct for the acute angle of right angled triangle?",
    "options": ["complementary", "supplementary", "adjacent", "equal"],
    "answer": "complementary"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "There are 60 students in a class. If 60% of them are girls, then how many boys in the class?",
    "options": ["24", "36", "18", "40"],
    "answer": "24"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Last year Hari was 4 feet tall, and this year he is 5 feet tall. What is the percent increase of his height?",
    "options": ["10%", "15%", "20%", "25%"],
    "answer": "25%"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the difference between 5 of 80 and 30% of 80?",
    "options": ["12", "18", "24", "20"],
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The cost of 6 pens is equal to the cost of the 10 pencils. If the cost of 4 pencils is Rs. 120, then what is the cost of 4 pens?",
    "options": ["100", "200", "300", "400"],
    "answer": "200"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the cost of 7 kg sugar is Rs. 210, how much sugar can be purchased for Rs. 330?",
    "options": ["11kg", "12kg", "13kg", "14kg"],
    "answer": "11kg"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Ganga can read 48 pages per hour. At this rate, how many pages she can read in 80 minutes?",
    "options": ["60", "72", "48", "64"],
    "answer": "64"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two numbers are in the ratio of 6:7 and their sum is 117, then what are these numbers?",
    "options": ["56, 58", "63, 54", "54, 63", "48, 56"],
    "answer": "54, 63"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 5:7 = 15:x, then what is the value of x?",
    "options": ["18", "21", "24", "35"],
    "answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If cost price of 8 pens and selling price of 10 pens is equal, then what is loss percentage?",
    "options": ["20%", "15%", "10%", "25%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the 20% discount is given on computer book costing Rs. 300, then what will be selling price?",
    "options": ["Rs. 240", "Rs. 220", "Rs. 260", "Rs. 250"],
    "answer": "Rs. 240"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A watch is bought at Rs. 250 and sold at Rs. 300, then what is the profit percentage?",
    "options": ["10%", "15%", "20%", "25%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% per anum?",
    "options": ["60 yrs.", "50 yrs.", "40 yrs.", "30 yrs."],
    "answer": "50 yrs."
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the rate percentage per anum that a sum of money trebles itself in 25 years?",
    "options": ["2%", "4%", "6%", "8%"],
    "answer": "8%"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the cardinal number of a vowel set \( V = \\{a, e, i, o, u\\} \)?",
    "options": ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the minimum value of \( n(P \\cap Q)? \) When \( n(U) = 100, n(P) = 70, \) and \( n(Q) = 45? \)",
    "options": ["15", "55", "30", "45"],
    "answer": "15"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is true for prime number?",
    "options": ["no factors", "only one factor", "only two factors", "more than two factors"],
    "answer": "only two factors"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following interval notation is correct for \(\\{x: 5 \\leq x \\leq 15\\}\)?",
    "options": ["[5, ∞]", "[∞, 15]", "[6, 14]", "[5, 15]"],
    "answer": "[5, 15]"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of 'x' when it is multiplied by 6 and added to 3 times its own number gives 63?",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of \( \\sqrt{\\square} \\cdot 2^7 \)",
    "options": ["20", "25", "10", "60"],
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the number of seconds in 13 hour?",
    "options": ["1200 sec", "2400 sec", "3600 sec", "4800 sec"],
    "answer": "4800 sec"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "In a kilometer race A beats B by 100 meters and B beats C by 150 meters. In the same race, by how many meters does A beats C?",
    "options": ["150 m", "100 m", "250 m", "200 m"],
    "answer": "250 m"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The area of 4 walls of square room is 120 m\(^2\). If the height is 5 m, then what is the area of its floor?",
    "options": ["26 m\(^2\)", "56 m\(^2\)", "25 m\(^2\)", "36 m\(^2\)"],
    "answer": "36 m\(^2\)"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the probability of death?",
    "options": ["1", "\(\\frac{1}{2}\)", "0", "∞"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the chance to give the birth by a pregnant lady on Tuesday?",
    "options": ["\(\\frac{3}{7}\)", "\(\\frac{1}{7}\)", "1", "\(\\frac{1}{2}\)"],
    "answer": "\(\\frac{1}{7}\)"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the BACHELOR is written as 12345678, then how will BCA be written?",
    "options": ["123", "432", "147", "132"],
    "answer": "132"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which one of the following is missing alphabet in given table? | T | Q | N | | P | O | S | | M | ? | R |",
    "options": ["K", "L", "N", "O"],
    "answer": "L"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Saru ranks 8\(^{th}\) from the top and 20\(^{th}\) from the bottom in class, then how many students are there in class room?",
    "options": ["28", "27", "20", "29"],
    "answer": "27"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Find the value of 'x' in series 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, x?",
    "options": ["21", "22", "23", "20"],
    "answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "How many squares in the following figure?",
    "options": ["13", "14", "15", "16"],
    "answer": "14"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of cos \( 0^9 \)?",
    "options": ["\(\\frac{1}{2}\)", "\(\\sqrt{\\frac{1}{2}}\)", "0", "1"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "When did the new constitute of Nepal \"Nepal Ko Sambidhan\" was released?",
    "options": ["2072 Ashoj 4", "2072 Ashoj 3", "2072 Ashoj 2", "2072 Ashoj 1"],
    "answer": "2072 Ashoj 3"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is known as \"Father of Computer\"?",
    "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Bill Gates", "Mark Zuckerberg", "John V Neumann"],
    "answer": "Charles Babbage"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following discipline is not awarded by noble prize?",
    "options": ["Literature", "Economics", "Physics", "Computer Science"],
    "answer": "Computer Science"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following belongs to SSD?",
    "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "Cache Memory", "Mass Storage"],
    "answer": "Mass Storage"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who won the FIFA World Cup 2018 held in Russia?",
    "options": ["England", "Croatia", "France", "Germany"],
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following is not an output device?",
    "options": ["OCR", "Plotter", "Monitor", "Printer"],
    "answer": "OCR"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "What is the scientific name of human?",
    "options": ["Rana Tigrina", "Homosepian", "Felis Catus", "Rattus"],
    "answer": "Homosepian"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which one of the following is the deepest river of the Nepal?",
    "options": ["Karnali", "Koshi", "Mahakali", "Gandaki"],
    "answer": "Gandaki"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first prime minister of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Janga Bahadur Rana", "Matrika Prasad Koirala", "Bhimsen Thapa", "Mathabar Sing Thapa"],
    "answer": "Bhimsen Thapa"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is the writer of the Nepal novel \"Basain\"?",
    "options": ["Lil Bahadur Kshetri", "Ramlal Joshi", "Gopal Prasad Rimal", "Lokendra Bahadur Chand"],
    "answer": "Lil Bahadur Kshetri"
  },
  
  {
    "id": 101,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "John ...... tennis once or twice a week.",
    "options": ["is playing usually", "is usually playing", "usually plays", "plays usually"],
    "answer": "usually plays"
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I would be ...... if you could send me details of your PS/Zrange.",
    "options": ["thankful", "please", "content", "grateful"],
    "answer": "grateful"
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "What is a LAN in computer networks?",
    "options": ["Literary Area Network", "Local Area Network", "Long Area Network", "Local Asian Network"],
    "answer": "Local Area Network"
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I've lost one of my gloves. I ...... it somewhere.",
    "options": ["must drop", "must have dropped", "must be dropping", "must have been dropping"],
    "answer": "must have dropped"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "An item of data such as a number, a name, or an address is called as ......",
    "options": ["logical record", "physical record", "field", "internal schema"],
    "answer": "field"
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "There's somebody walking behind us. I think ......",
    "options": ["we are following", "we are being followed", "we are followed", "we are being following"],
    "answer": "we are being followed"
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The feminine gender of bachelor is called a ......",
    "options": ["spinster", "bride", "sister", "countess"],
    "answer": "spinster"
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The police officer stopped us and asked us where ......",
    "options": ["were we going", "are we going", "we are going", "we were going"],
    "answer": "we were going"
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The procedure for ...... a new file is very simple.",
    "options": ["create", "created", "creating", "creation"],
    "answer": "creating"
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Call an ambulance. There's been ......",
    "options": ["accident", "an accident", "some accident", "a accident"],
    "answer": "an accident"
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "They live on a busy road ...... a lot of noise from the traffic.",
    "options": ["It must be", "There must be", "There must have", "It must have"],
    "answer": "There must be"
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I don't like stories ...... have unhappy endings.",
    "options": ["that", "they", "while", "who"],
    "answer": "that"
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The exam was quite easy ...... We expected.",
    "options": ["more easy that", "more easy than", "easier than", "easier as"],
    "answer": "easier than"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "You should insure your bicycle ...... stolen.",
    "options": ["in case it will be", "if it will be", "in case it is", "if it is"],
    "answer": "in case it is"
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I'm going away ...... the end of January.",
    "options": ["at", "on", "in", "to"],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "She has learnt ...... (now she knows how to cook.)",
    "options": ["cooking", "cooked", "to cook", "to cooking"],
    "answer": "to cook"
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The word 'Photographic' has its principal stress on the ...... syllable.",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd", "4th"],
    "answer": "3rd"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "It is getting dark. We ...... a taxi.",
    "options": ["had better taken", "had better to take", "had better take", "had better took"],
    "answer": "had better take"
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... you ...... had, you would have succeeded in the examination.",
    "options": ["If, had", "Had, work", "Had, worked", "If, worked"],
    "answer": "Had, worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I bought a pen, a pencil, a sharpper and a water bottle, It has a ......",
    "options": ["Rising Tone", "Rising Tone + Falling Tone", "Falling Tone + Falling Tone", "Falling Tone + Rising Tone"],
    "answer": "Falling Tone + Rising Tone"
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... tired, I went to bed early.",
    "options": ["Felt", "To fell", "Feeling", "Having to feel"],
    "answer": "Feeling"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The antonym of 'sharp' is",
    "options": ["slow", "blunt", "hard", "thin"],
    "answer": "blunt"
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Please ...... enclosed our current catalogue and price list.",
    "options": ["find", "look", "receive", "examine"],
    "answer": "find"
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... she has written some interesting stories.",
    "options": ["Late", "Lately", "Later", "Later"],
    "answer": "Lately"
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "We look forward ...... from you.",
    "options": ["hear", "to hear", "hearing", "to hearing"],
    "answer": "to hearing"
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "By next Monday, he ...... his job.",
    "options": ["will change", "will have changed", "changes", "will be changing"],
    "answer": "will have changed"
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The negative statement of \"He used to live here.\" is ......",
    "options": ["He used not to live here", "He never used to live here", "Did he used to live here?", "both a) and b)"],
    "answer": "He used not to live here"
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "A device moved by hand to indicate position on the screen is ......",
    "options": ["mainframe", "icon", "microchip", "mouse"],
    "answer": "mouse"
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "...... contains all the information we need.",
    "options": ["These books", "These book", "This books", "This book"],
    "answer": "This book"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "…… rice that the shopkeeper showed me was of an inferior quality.",
    "options": ["The little", "A little", "Little", "Few"],
    "answer": "The little"
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "He'd rather stay back ……?",
    "options": ["hadn't he", "didn't he", "Would not he", "wouldn't he"],
    "answer": "wouldn't he"
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "We …… him if he treats the customers rudely.",
    "options": ["dismiss", "dismissed", "will dismiss", "would dismiss"],
    "answer": "will dismiss"
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Should you require anything further at this time, please do not …… to contact me.",
    "options": ["void", "hesitate", "delay", "prevent"],
    "answer": "hesitate"
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The active of: \"My money was picked yesterday\" is ……",
    "options": ["Somebody picked my money yesterday.", "Somebody had picked my money yesterday.", "Somebody picked my money.", "Somebody picked my money the other day."],
    "answer": "Somebody picked my money yesterday."
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Of the two sisters Anu is ……",
    "options": ["taller", "tall", "the tallest", "the taller"],
    "answer": "the taller"
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Why does the author compare 'nature' to business?",
    "options": ["Because of the capital depletion in nature and business.", "Because of the similarity with which one should use both.", "Because of the same interest level yield.", "Because of the diversity of the various capital inputs."],
    "answer": "Because of the similarity with which one should use both."
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "\"The folly our descendants are least likely to forgive us.\" What is the business equivalent of the folly the author is referring to?",
    "options": ["Reducing the profit margin", "Not pumping some money out of profits into the business", "Eroding the capital lease of the business", "Putting interest on capital back into the business"],
    "answer": "Eroding the capital lease of the business"
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is false in context of the given passage?",
    "options": ["The diversity of plant life is essential for human existence.", "Scientists know the usefulness of most plant species.", "Chemicals for cancer treatment are available from plants.", "There are around ten times the plant species undiscovered as compared to the discovered ones."],
    "answer": "Scientists know the usefulness of most plant species."
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following correctly reflects the opinion of the author to take care of hunger in the world?",
    "options": ["Increase the number of edible plants being cultivates.", "Increase cultivation of the 150 species presently under cultivation.", "Increase the cultivation of medical plants.", "Increase the potential of the uncultivated edible plants."],
    "answer": "Increase the number of edible plants being cultivates."
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which of the following is mentioned as the immediate cause for the destruction of plant species?",
    "options": ["Soil Erosion", "Destruction of habitat", "Cultivation", "Agricultural practices"],
    "answer": "Agricultural practices"
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "For some integer m, which of the following form is odd integer?",
    "options": ["m", "m + 1", "2m", "2m + 1"],
    "answer": "2m + 1"
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two lines are perpendicular if the product of their slopes is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "-1", "2"],
    "answer": "-1"
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Graphically, the pair of equations 6x-3y+10=0 and 2x-y+9=0 represents two lines which are:",
    "options": ["Intersecting at exactly one point.", "Intersecting at exactly two points.", "Coincident.", "Parallel"],
    "answer": "Parallel"
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "In the given figure, ∠T and ∠B are right angles. If the length of AT, BC and AS are 15, 16, and 17 cm respectively, then the length of TC is:",
    "options": ["18 cm", "16 cm", "19 cm", "12 cm"],
    "answer": "18 cm"
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If |A|=0, then A is",
    "options": ["zero matrix", "singular matrix", "non-singular matrix", "Identity matrix"],
    "answer": "singular matrix"
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Two bicycles were sold for Rs. 3990 each, gaining 5% on one and losing 5% on the other. The gain or loss percent on the whole transaction is",
    "options": ["Neither gain nor loss", "2.5% gain", "2.5% loss", "0.25% loss"],
    "answer": "0.25% loss"
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 72×96=6927, 58×87=7885, then 79×86 is",
    "options": ["7689", "8976", "6897"],
    "answer": "6897"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A ladder 15 meters long just reaches the top of a vertical wall. If the ladder makes an angle of 60° with the wall, then the height of the wall will be",
    "options": ["7.5m", "7.7m", "8.5m", "8.8m"],
    "answer": "7.5m"
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The famous mathematician associated with finding the sum of the first 100 natural numbers is",
    "options": ["Pythagoras", "Newton", "Gauss", "Euclid"],
    "answer": "Gauss"
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Sum of the series 1+12+132+143+⋯+21+321+431+⋯ is",
    "options": ["1", "2", "1.555", "1.7555"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The AM between x-3 and x+5 is",
    "options": ["2x+2", "x-1", "x+1", "2x+1"],
    "answer": "x+1"
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of sin60°cos30°+sin30°cos60° is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "4"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If sinθ−cosθ=0 then the value of θ is",
    "options": ["30°", "90°", "60°", "45°"],
    "answer": "45°"
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A TV is purchased at Rs. 5000 and sold at Rs. 4000, the loss percent is",
    "options": ["10%", "20%", "25%", "28%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the cost price is 25% of selling price. Then the profit percent is",
    "options": ["75%", "200%", "300%", "25%"],
    "answer": "300%"
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A man buys an item at Rs. 1200 and sells it at the loss of 20 percent. Then what is the selling price of that item",
    "options": ["Rs. 660", "Rs. 760", "Rs. 860", "Rs. 960"],
    "answer": "Rs. 960"
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The mean of the data: 4, 10, 5, 9, 12 is:",
    "options": ["8", "10", "9", "15"],
    "answer": "8"
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A dice is thrown in the air. The probability of getting odd numbers is",
    "options": ["1/2", "3/4", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "1/2"
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If we throw two coins in the air, then the probability of getting both tails will be",
    "options": ["1/2", "1/4", "2", "4"],
    "answer": "1/4"
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The distance of point A(2,4) from x-axis is",
    "options": ["2", "4", "6", "20"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of 6+6+66+6+6 is:",
    "options": ["4", "3", "3.5", "-3"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A function f(x) is said to be an odd function if",
    "options": ["f(x)=f(x)", "f(-x)=-f(x)", "f(x)=k where k is a constant", "f(x)=k+f(x) where k is an odd number"],
    "answer": "f(-x)=-f(x)"
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The set A=(x:x<=N and x2+3x+2=0) is",
    "options": ["Null set", "Finite set", "Infinite set", "Set with two elements."],
    "answer": "Null set"
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number of subsets of a set containing n elements is",
    "options": ["n²", "2n", "2n−1", "2n"],
    "answer": "2n"
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "For a set A, (AC)C is",
    "options": ["U−A", "AC", "UC", "A"],
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Range of the function f(x)=x/|x| is",
    "options": ["{1}", "{1, −1}", "{0}", "(−∞, ∞)"],
    "answer": "{1, −1}"
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of i−51 is",
    "options": ["1", "−1", "i", "−i"],
    "answer": "i"
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of limx->0 sinx/x is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "−1", "None of these"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Derivative of ln2x with respect to x is",
    "options": ["2x", "1/2x", "1/x", "x"],
    "answer": "1/x"
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Value of limx->2 (x2−4)/(x−2) is",
    "options": ["0", "4", "0/0", "∞"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the area of the shaded region in the adjoining diagram?",
    "options": ["6cm²", "7cm²", "8cm²", "9cm²"],
    "answer": "6cm²"
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A can do a piece of work in 10 days and B can do it in 15 days. How many days will it take if they work together?",
    "options": ["4", "6", "5", "7"],
    "answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The solution of the equation x2+1=0 in complex number system is,",
    "options": ["1", "-1", "0", "±i"],
    "answer": "±i"
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the value of x in equation 4x=1/4",
    "options": ["1/4", "1/2", "-1", "1"],
    "answer": "-1"
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of 0! is",
    "options": ["0", "10", "1", "∞"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If a square has side 10 cm then diagonal is:",
    "options": ["15 cm", "10√2 cm", "20 cm", "12 cm"],
    "answer": "10√2 cm"
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If TP and TQ are the two tangents to a circle with centre O so that ∠POQ=110∘, then ∠PTQ is equal to",
    "options": ["70∘", "80∘", "90∘", "110∘"],
    "answer": "70∘"
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Area of an equilateral triangle with side length a is equal to",
    "options": ["(√3/2)a", "(3/2)a²", "(√3/4)a²", "(3/4)a"],
    "answer": "(√3/4)a²"
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which function is even function?",
    "options": ["f(x)=sin√x", "f(x)=cos√x", "f(x)=x²-2x", "f(x)=e^x"],
    "answer": "f(x)=cos√x"
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The product of a rational and an irrational number is:",
    "options": ["Always an integer", "Always a rational number", "Always an irrational number", "Sometimes rational and sometimes irrational"],
    "answer": "Always an irrational number"
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of (16)^(1/2) is",
    "options": ["1/16", "1/2", "4", "1/4"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number, (3-√3)(3+√3) is",
    "options": ["an irrational number", "a rational number", "not a natural number", "none of these"],
    "answer": "a rational number"
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A trapezium has:",
    "options": ["One pair of opposite sides parallel", "Two pair of opposite sides parallel to each other", "All its sides are equal", "All angles are equal"],
    "answer": "One pair of opposite sides parallel"
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is the angle made by line the x+y+1=0 with x-axis?",
    "options": ["90°", "120°", "135°", "180°"],
    "answer": "135°"
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The zero's of the quadratic equation x²-5x+6 are",
    "options": ["5 and 6", "-5 and -6", "2 and 3", "-2 and -3"],
    "answer": "2 and 3"
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A person took a loan of Rs 1500 from his employer for 3 months at 12% per annum simple interest. The amount he has to be return is:",
    "options": ["Rs. 1500", "Rs. 1545", "Rs. 1555", "Rs. 1575"],
    "answer": "Rs. 1545"
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 5^(x+3)=25^x then value of x is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x<0 then |x| is equal to",
    "options": ["-x", "x", "0", "1"],
    "answer": "-x"
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x+y=3 and x²+y²=5 then value of xy is",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The range of the function f(x)=3x-2, is",
    "options": ["(−∞,∞)", "R={3}", "(−∞,0)", "(0,−∞)"],
    "answer": "(−∞,∞)"
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is the author of the novel 'Seto Dharati'?",
    "options": ["Amar Neupane", "Subin Bhattarai", "Buddhisagar", "Jhamak Ghimire"],
    "answer": "Amar Neupane"
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "When was Tri-Chandra College established?",
    "options": ["1985 BS", "1975 BS", "1990 BS", "2016 BS"],
    "answer": "1975 BS"
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "What is the full form of PDF in computer file?",
    "options": ["Processed Document File", "Protected Document Format", "Partial Document File", "Portable Document Format"],
    "answer": "Portable Document Format"
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first programmer in computer?",
    "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Lady Ada Lovelace", "Bill Gates", "John Napier"],
    "answer": "Lady Ada Lovelace"
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "How many players are there in Cricket?",
    "options": ["6", "8", "11", "15"],
    "answer": "11"
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who discovered the America?",
    "options": ["Shakespeare", "Columbus", "George Washington", "Michael Goryachov"],
    "answer": "Columbus"
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who was the first prime minister of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Janga Bahadur Rana", "Bir Shamsher", "Bhimsen Thapa", "Tanka Prasad Acharya"],
    "answer": "Bhimsen Thapa"
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The recent height of Mt. Everest is:",
    "options": ["8848 m", "8840 m", "8848.86 m", "8848.42 m"],
    "answer": "8848.86 m"
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "How many districts are there in Nepal?",
    "options": ["74", "75", "77", "76"],
    "answer": "77"
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which is the biggest province of Nepal?",
    "options": ["Gandaki Pradesh", "Sudhurpashchim Pradesh", "Karnati Pradesh", "Bagnati Pradesh"],
    "answer": "Karnati Pradesh"
  },  
  {
    "id": 201,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "To beg the question.",
    "options": ["to refer to", "to take for granted", "to raise objections", "to be discussed"],
    "answer": "to take for granted"
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Cricket is a......game, but the destiny of the side is often shaped by a couple of individuals.",
    "options": ["good", "team", "popular", "new"],
    "answer": "team"
  },
  {
    "id": 203,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The ......has to be precisely stated.",
    "options": ["content", "criticism", "case", "theme"],
    "answer": "theme"
  },
  {
    "id": 204,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Man worked with his small tools until the advent of modern machinery......by steam and electricity.",
    "options": ["worked", "controlled", "driven", "moved"],
    "answer": "driven"
  },
  {
    "id": 205,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The rest is history.",
    "options": ["history takes rest", "known to everyone", "to avoid historical facts", "history repeats"],
    "answer": "known to everyone"
  },
  {
    "id": 206,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Warm as toast.",
    "options": ["very hot", "very fresh", "lukewarm", "Cold"],
    "answer": "very fresh"
  },
  {
    "id": 207,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The economy is finally ......",
    "options": ["looking in", "looking on", "looking at", "looking up"],
    "answer": "looking up"
  },
  {
    "id": 208,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The synonym of \"Alien\" is:",
    "options": ["Citizen", "Native", "Accustomed", "Stranger"],
    "answer": "Stranger"
  },
  {
    "id": 209,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"Foster\":",
    "options": ["Rear", "Encourage", "Nourish", "Promote"],
    "answer": "Rear"
  },
  {
    "id": 210,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"Witty\":",
    "options": ["Ingenious", "Speedy", "Foolish", "Awkward"],
    "answer": "Ingenious"
  },
  {
    "id": 211,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The antonym of \"Abolish\" is:",
    "options": ["remove", "reside", "confront", "establish"],
    "answer": "establish"
  },
  {
    "id": 212,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Give the antonym \"Salient\":",
    "options": ["emphatic", "striking", "important", "incline"],
    "answer": "incline"
  },
  {
    "id": 213,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Demonstrating good judgement is called:",
    "options": ["insinuate", "judicious", "masterpiece", "towering"],
    "answer": "judicious"
  },
  {
    "id": 214,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The study of society is called:",
    "options": ["Meteorology", "archeology", "Sociology", "geology"],
    "answer": "Sociology"
  },
  {
    "id": 215,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Badminton is played on a court as wrestling in a",
    "options": ["court", "track", "ground", "Arena"],
    "answer": "Arena"
  },
  {
    "id": 216,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "It was the help he got from his friends which………him through the tragedy.",
    "options": ["boosted", "parked", "supported", "helped"],
    "answer": "helped"
  },
  {
    "id": 217,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I never miss a cricket match. I………fond of cricket since childhood.",
    "options": ["am", "will be", "have been", "has been"],
    "answer": "have been"
  },
  {
    "id": 218,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "What is the opposite of \"Mute\"?",
    "options": ["diversity", "quicken", "harmonize", "amplify"],
    "answer": "amplify"
  },
  {
    "id": 219,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The scientists made a ...... discovery for which he was honored.",
    "options": ["sensual", "sensational", "sensuous", "sentimental"],
    "answer": "sensational"
  },
  {
    "id": 220,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "That charming girl was the ...... of all eyes.",
    "options": ["aim", "target", "ambition", "cynosure"],
    "answer": "cynosure"
  },
  {
    "id": 221,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "A son who is unable to look his father on the face is:",
    "options": ["guilty", "arrogant", "timid", "ashamed"],
    "answer": "ashamed"
  },
  {
    "id": 222,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "He resembles ...... his mother.",
    "options": ["at", "in", "with", "none of these"],
    "answer": "none of these"
  },
  {
    "id": 223,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The thunder was accompanied ...... heavy rains.",
    "options": ["by", "with", "through", "up"],
    "answer": "with"
  },
  {
    "id": 224,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "We passed ...... a lot of beautiful towns on the way to the resort.",
    "options": ["along", "across", "through", "all"],
    "answer": "through"
  },
  {
    "id": 225,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "The child was hiding ...... the door.",
    "options": ["behind", "below", "among", "none"],
    "answer": "behind"
  },
  {
    "id": 226,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "My parents got married ...... the 1970s.",
    "options": ["at", "in", "from", "on"],
    "answer": "in"
  },
  {
    "id": 227,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Many of us eat ...... fork and spoon.",
    "options": ["of", "on", "to", "with"],
    "answer": "with"
  },
  {
    "id": 228,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "How many people are ...... your team?",
    "options": ["of", "on", "to", "with"],
    "answer": "on"
  },
  {
    "id": 229,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "I brought him ...... with great difficulty.",
    "options": ["up", "about", "round", "in"],
    "answer": "up"
  },
  {
    "id": 230,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Give an example pertinent ...... the case.",
    "options": ["on", "to", "for", "with"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 231,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "You will have to catch the morning flight, so you ...... better get ready.",
    "options": ["would", "should", "had", "may"],
    "answer": "should"
  },
  {
    "id": 232,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Leaps and bounds.",
    "options": ["in brief", "delay", "rapidly", "financial crisis"],
    "answer": "rapidly"
  },
  {
    "id": 233,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Take up the cutgeis.",
    "options": ["to disturb", "to support", "to follow", "to appreciate"],
    "answer": "to support"
  },
  {
    "id": 234,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Spick and span.",
    "options": ["in order", "disorder", "all qualities", "no quality"],
    "answer": "in order"
  },
  {
    "id": 235,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Take to heels.",
    "options": ["to wait", "to run away", "to dance", "to follow"],
    "answer": "to run away"
  },
  {
    "id": 236,
    "type": "english",
    "question": "Under the cloud.",
    "options": ["to be a secret", "amazing", "to be under suspicion", "feel good factor"],
    "answer": "to be under suspicion"
  },
  {
    "id": 241,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The slope of the straight line that passes through the point (-1,0) and (3,8) is:",
    "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"],
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 242,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The probability of sample space is:",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 243,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number of subsets of set of order 5 is:",
    "options": ["16", "32", "8", "24"],
    "answer": "32"
  },
  {
    "id": 244,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of √3/√9 is:",
    "options": ["rational number", "irrational number", "imaginary number", "none of these"],
    "answer": "rational number"
  },
  {
    "id": 245,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If the function f(x)=x²-5, then f(√5) is equal to",
    "options": ["0", "5", "10", "none of these"],
    "answer": "0"
  },
  {
    "id": 246,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The sum of 1st n natural no. of A.P is 55, the value of n is:",
    "options": ["10", "12", "14", "16"],
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "id": 247,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of tan 60° is:",
    "options": ["√3/2", "√3/2", "√3", "1"],
    "answer": "√3"
  },
  {
    "id": 248,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If A and B are arbitrary square matrices of same order, then:",
    "options": ["(AB)′ = AB", "(AB)′ = AB", "AB = BA′", "(A + B)′ = A′ - B′"],
    "answer": "(AB)′ = AB"
  },
  {
    "id": 249,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A room is 12m long and 10m wide. If the area of 4 walls is 176m², the height of the room is:",
    "options": ["5m²", "4m", "3m²", "6m"],
    "answer": "4m"
  },
  {
    "id": 250,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of 2¹² + 2¹² + 2¹² + 2¹² is:",
    "options": ["2¹⁴", "4¹⁶", "2¹⁶", "2⁴⁸"],
    "answer": "2¹⁴"
  },
  {
    "id": 251,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If A and B are the nonsingular matrices, then,",
    "options": ["(AB)′ = A⁻¹B⁻¹", "AB = BA", "(AB)¹ = A¹B¹", "(AB)¹ = B¹A¹"],
    "answer": "(AB)¹ = B¹A¹"
  },
  {
    "id": 252,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What is 30% of the 20% of 10% of x?",
    "options": ["0.006x%", "0.6x%", "0.06%", "none of these"],
    "answer": "0.06%"
  },
  {
    "id": 253,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The difference between 3% of 80 and 30% of 80 is:",
    "options": ["15", "10", "24", "20"],
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "id": 254,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "In a company with 180 employees, 108 of the employees are female. What percent of the employees are male?",
    "options": ["5%", "25%", "35%", "40%"],
    "answer": "40%"
  },
  {
    "id": 255,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% p.a is:",
    "options": ["35 yrs", "70yrs", "50yrs", "30yrs"],
    "answer": "50yrs"
  },
  {
    "id": 256,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "By selling 33m of cloth one gains the selling price of 11m.The gain percent is:",
    "options": ["20%", "40%", "50%", "22%"],
    "answer": "50%"
  },
  {
    "id": 257,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Hari sold a radio for Rs.750 with Rs.25 loss. His loss percentage is:",
    "options": ["3.33%", "3.225%", "3.45%", "3.49%"],
    "answer": "3.33%"
  },
  {
    "id": 258,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Area of a rectangle is 150 sq.m. it's one side is 15m, the height of the rectangle is:",
    "options": ["8m", "10m", "12m", "16m"],
    "answer": "10m"
  },
  {
    "id": 259,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The formula to calculate the area of kite is:",
    "options": ["½ d₁*d₂", "√3/4a", "√s(s-a)(s-b)(s-c)", "None of these"],
    "answer": "½ d₁*d₂"
  },
  {
    "id": 260,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A dealer altered his trade discount from 15% to 10%, what percentage was the selling price altered?",
    "options": ["5.56%", "5.88%", "6.88%", "5.63%"],
    "answer": "5.56%"
  },
  {
    "id": 261,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "An article was sold for Rs.415 at a loss of 17%, what would have been the sale price?",
    "options": ["Rs.475", "Rs.490", "Rs.500", "Rs.525"],
    "answer": "Rs.500"
  },
  {
    "id": 262,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of sin135° is:",
    "options": ["√2/2", "√3/2", "1/√2", "1/√3"],
    "answer": "1/√2"
  },
  {
    "id": 263,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The time in years that the sum of money double itself at 10% per annum of interest is:",
    "options": ["20yrs", "10.5yrs", "12yrs", "10yrs"],
    "answer": "10yrs"
  },
  {
    "id": 264,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Today is the birthday of Rahul and he is 3 times as old as Nirmala. In 13 years, Rahul will be one year less than twice as old as Nirmala will be then. The age of Rahul today is:",
    "options": ["30yrs", "36yrs", "49yrs", "30yrs"],
    "answer": "30yrs"
  },
  {
    "id": 265,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A number consists of two digits. The sum of its digits is 16. If 18 is subtracted from the number, the digits are interchanged. The number is:",
    "options": ["73", "72", "97", "24"],
    "answer": "97"
  },
  {
    "id": 266,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The breadth of a room 4m high is one third of its length. If the cost of painting its wall at the rate of Rs.5 per m² is Rs.640,the cost of carpeting at the rate of Rs.250 per m² is:",
    "options": ["11000", "12000", "13000", "14000"],
    "answer": "12000"
  },
  {
    "id": 267,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 7a-b=23 and 7b-a=31, the value of a+b is:",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
    "answer": "9"
  },
  {
    "id": 268,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The value of |(-2-3)-(-2-3)| is:",
    "options": ["5", "4", "3", "2"],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 269,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If f(x)=x¹/⁴+x¹/², the value of f(16) is:",
    "options": ["6", "8", "32", "64"],
    "answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "id": 270,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Which is not true? i.(Aᵀ)ᵀ=A ii.(A+B)ᵀ=AᵀBᵀ iii.(AB)ᵀ=AᵀBᵀ iv.(KA)ᵀ=KAᵀ, where k is a scalar",
    "options": ["i", "ii", "iii", "iv"],
    "answer": "iii"
  },
  {
    "id": 271,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The system of equations 2x+6y=6 and 6x+9y=18 have:",
    "options": ["unique solution", "no solution", "infinitely many solutions", "none of these"],
    "answer": "unique solution"
  },
  {
    "id": 272,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The ratio compounded of 4:9, the duplicate ratio of 3:4 is:",
    "options": ["1:4", "1:3", "3:1", "5:6"],
    "answer": "5:6"
  },
  {
    "id": 273,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x:y=6:5, the value of (5x/3y):(5x-3y) is equal to:",
    "options": ["2:1", "3:1", "5:3", "5:2"],
    "answer": "3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 274,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 5x+13=31, the value of √(5x+31) is:",
    "options": ["5", "6", "7", "8"],
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "id": 275,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The width of a rectangle is 2cm less than its length and its length and perimeter is 12cm. The area of rectangle is:",
    "options": ["12cm²", "24cm²", "18cm²", "8cm²"],
    "answer": "18cm²"
  },
  {
    "id": 276,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If x-7=1, the value of x+19 is:",
    "options": ["19", "27", "38", "42"],
    "answer": "27"
  },
  {
    "id": 277,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The equation of the line that passes through (4,-4) and (4,4) is:",
    "options": ["x=4", "y=4", "y=4x", "y=4x+4"],
    "answer": "x=4"
  },
  {
    "id": 278,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If -7≤x≤7 and 0≤y≤12, the greatest possible value of y-x is:",
    "options": ["5", "4", "3", "2"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 279,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If a,b,c are in GP, then",
    "options": ["b²=ac", "b(a²+c²)=a(a²+b²)", "b=(a+b)/2", "none of these"],
    "answer": "b²=ac"
  },
  {
    "id": 280,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 13,p,q,r and 29 are in AP,the value of p,q and r are:",
    "options": ["17,21,25", "17,22,23", "11,19,21", "none of these"],
    "answer": "17,21,25"
  },
  {
    "id": 281,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "What price should a shopkeeper mark on an article,coming him Rs.153 to gain 20%,after allowing a discount of 15%?",
    "options": ["Rs.224", "Rs.216", "Rs.154", "Rs.162"],
    "answer": "Rs.216"
  },
  {
    "id": 282,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A sold an article with Rs.250 profit which is 15% in equivalent. The cost price of the article is:",
    "options": ["Rs.1688.8", "Rs.1666.67", "Rs.1676.70", "Rs.1677.70"],
    "answer": "Rs.1676.70"
  },
  {
    "id": 283,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Ramita sold a skirt for Rs.500 where she had a loss of 1% of the cost price. The cost price of the skirt is:",
    "options": ["605", "556", "506", "600"],
    "answer": "556"
  },
  {
    "id": 284,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "A dealer marks his goods 60% above the cost price. What percent of discount must be allowed, if he makes a profit of 20% only?",
    "options": ["20%", "25%", "12%", "30%"],
    "answer": "20%"
  },
  {
    "id": 285,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If 20% discount was given on math books costing Rs.250, the selling price S.P is:",
    "options": ["Rs.150", "Rs.100", "Rs.250", "Rs.200"],
    "answer": "Rs.200"
  },
  {
    "id": 286,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If A = [[1,0,0],[0,1,0]], the value of A⁵ is",
    "options": ["[[1,0,0],[0,1,0]]", "[[-1,0,0],[0,1,0]]", "[[1,0,0],[0,-1,0]]", "[[2,-3,-4]]"],
    "answer": "[[1,0,0],[0,1,0]]"
  },
  {
    "id": 287,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The number of solutions 2x+y=4, x-2y=3, 3x+5y=6 is:",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 288,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "Shyam lost 15% by selling his old book for Rs.170. For how much he must have sold it to gain 15%?",
    "options": ["Rs184", "Rs.194", "Rs.230", "Rs.224"],
    "answer": "Rs.230"
  },
  {
    "id": 289,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "If a plot is for Rs.18,700, the owner losses 15%. Find the price at which it must be sold to gain 25%?",
    "options": ["Rs.27000", "Rs.27500", "Rs.29000", "Rs.38000"],
    "answer": "Rs.27500"
  },
  {
    "id": 290,
    "type": "math",
    "question": "The selling price of four articles equals to cost price of 5 articles. The gain is:",
    "options": ["20%", "25%", "28%", "80%"],
    "answer": "25%"
  },
  {
    "id": 291,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The famous Manakamana Temple is situated in:",
    "options": ["Gorkha", "Chitwan", "Tanahun", "Dhading"],
    "answer": "Gorkha"
  },
  {
    "id": 292,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The Eiffel tower is situated in:",
    "options": ["London", "Tokyo", "Paris", "Madrid"],
    "answer": "Paris"
  },
  {
    "id": 293,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which of the following is not programming language?",
    "options": ["C#", "JAVA", "Python", "Arduino"],
    "answer": "Arduino"
  },
  {
    "id": 294,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The largest network category based on coverage area is:",
    "options": ["LAN", "MAN", "WAN", "none of these"],
    "answer": "WAN"
  },
  {
    "id": 295,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "How many permanent members are there in security council of UN?",
    "options": ["2", "10", "4", "5"],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "id": 296,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Rafael Nadal is associated with:",
    "options": ["Cricket", "Lawn Tennis", "Hockey", "Wrestling"],
    "answer": "Lawn Tennis"
  },
  {
    "id": 297,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The first President of Nepal is:",
    "options": ["Bidhya Devi Bhandari", "Pushpa kamal Dahal", "Sher Bahadur Deuba", "Dr.Ram Baran Yadav"],
    "answer": "Dr.Ram Baran Yadav"
  },
  {
    "id": 298,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "The letter 's' in HTTPs understands for",
    "options": ["Scared", "Secured", "Shape", "Shine"],
    "answer": "Secured"
  },
  {
    "id": 299,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Who is the captain of Nepal's National Cricket team?",
    "options": ["Anil Gurung", "Gyanendra Malla", "Rohit Poudel", "Parash Khadka"],
    "answer": "Parash Khadka"
  },
  {
    "id": 300,
    "type": "gk",
    "question": "Which city is known as 'City of Temples'?",
    "options": ["Phuket", "New York", "Kathmandu", "Rome"],
    "answer": "Kathmandu"
  },
  {
  "id": 301,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Above Board",
  "options": ["boasting person", "honest and straightforward", "a man with arrogance", "a dishonest person"],
  "answer": "honest and straightforward"
},
{
  "id": 302,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Call a spade a spade",
  "options": ["to disrespect", "to say in anger", "to speak plainly", "to manipulate"],
  "answer": "to speak plainly"
},
{
  "id": 303,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Roots and branch",
  "options": ["entirely", "step by step", "part by part", "bare truth"],
  "answer": "entirely"
},
{
  "id": 304,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Broadly speaking letters may be said to ...... into two categories.",
  "options": ["belong", "fall", "split", "convert"],
  "answer": "fall"
},
{
  "id": 305,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The last decade has been ...... for management education and development.",
  "options": ["dogmatic", "paradoxical", "praiseworthy", "outstanding"],
  "answer": "outstanding"
},
{
  "id": 306,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Bandy words",
  "options": ["to argue", "to request", "to give respect", "to be polite"],
  "answer": "to argue"
},
{
  "id": 307,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Ever and Anon",
  "options": ["true promise", "false promise", "frequent", "sometimes"],
  "answer": "sometimes"
},
{
  "id": 308,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The synonym of “Spurious” is:",
  "options": ["false", "harmful", "poisonous", "foreign"],
  "answer": "false"
},
{
  "id": 309,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of “Annex”.",
  "options": ["add", "low", "copy", "initial"],
  "answer": "add"
},
{
  "id": 310,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give an exact synonym of “Concert”.",
  "options": ["beauty", "power", "agreement", "none of these"],
  "answer": "agreement"
},
{
  "id": 311,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The antonym of “Engage” is:",
  "options": ["abstain", "liberate", "release", "join"],
  "answer": "abstain"
},
{
  "id": 312,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give the antonym “Fable”.",
  "options": ["truth", "fact", "reality", "actuality"],
  "answer": "fact"
},
{
  "id": 313,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "What is the antonym of “Moist”?",
  "options": ["parched", "dry", "hard", "crisp"],
  "answer": "dry"
},
{
  "id": 314,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The meaning of “shimmer” is:",
  "options": ["to flicker like sunlight", "to shine like sunlight", "to move like sunlight", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "all of the above"
},
{
  "id": 315,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The word “Snub” gives the meaning as:",
  "options": ["to ignore", "to avoid", "to shun", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "all of the above"
},
{
  "id": 316,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The enemy paid a large sum as......",
  "options": ["redress", "amends", "compensation", "punishment"],
  "answer": "compensation"
},
{
  "id": 317,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "......is a person who dabbles in arts and letters.",
  "options": ["chauvinist", "connoisseur", "philistine", "dilettante"],
  "answer": "dilettante"
},
{
  "id": 318,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We lost confidence on him because he never ...... the grandiose promises he made.",
  "options": ["forgot", "tired", "delivered on", "Relied upon"],
  "answer": "delivered on"
},
{
  "id": 319,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "His ...... in his family's position is great but he does not boast about it.",
  "options": ["status", "pride", "deceit", "presumption"],
  "answer": "status"
},
{
  "id": 320,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Even when murunga's reputation was in ...... almost everyone was willing to admit that he had genius.",
  "options": ["failure", "rebuttal", "accumulation", "eclipse"],
  "answer": "eclipse"
},
{
  "id": 321,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Shyam was no control ...... his temper.",
  "options": ["after", "in", "over", "at"],
  "answer": "over"
},
{
  "id": 322,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "She could not dissociate herself ...... what she said earlier.",
  "options": ["of", "with", "off", "from"],
  "answer": "from"
},
{
  "id": 323,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We travelled ...... a boat to reachdhaka.",
  "options": ["for", "on", "about", "by"],
  "answer": "by"
},
{
  "id": 324,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I am used ...... such hardships.",
  "options": ["for", "at", "from", "to"],
  "answer": "to"
},
{
  "id": 325,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I was disappointed ...... not finding the doctor in his seat.",
  "options": ["from", "on", "at", "in"],
  "answer": "at"
},
{
  "id": 326,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Ram is confident ...... his success.",
  "options": ["for", "about", "towards", "of"],
  "answer": "of"
},
{
  "id": 327,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The reward was not commensurate ...... the work done by us.",
  "options": ["on", "for", "with", "order"],
  "answer": "with"
},
{
  "id": 328,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The citizens must not murmur ...... new taxes.",
  "options": ["over", "upon", "against", "with"],
  "answer": "against"
},
{
  "id": 329,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "What do you infer ...... this boy's hesitating behavior?",
  "options": ["from", "for", "with", "against"],
  "answer": "with"
},
{
  "id": 330,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Beggar begged money......me.",
  "options": ["to", "from", "by", "with"],
  "answer": "from"
},
{
  "id": 331,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The word ‘profuse’ is meant for:",
  "options": ["not many", "an average number", "great abundance", "correct amount"],
  "answer": "great abundance"
},
{
  "id": 332,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give a wide berth",
  "options": ["to welcome", "to applaud", "to motivate", "to avoid"],
  "answer": "to avoid"
},
{
  "id": 333,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "When the church comes",
  "options": ["moment of decision", "destination", "dotage", "win something"],
  "answer": "moment of decision"
},
{
  "id": 334,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "benevolent is meant to:",
  "options": ["generous", "kind", "good", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "all of the above"
},
{
  "id": 335,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Pyrrhic victory",
  "options": ["great victory", "victory with a policy", "much awaited victory", "victory at a high cost"],
  "answer": "victory at a high cost"
},
{
  "id": 336,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Set people by ears.",
  "options": ["to incite people", "to listen carefully", "to give a long speech", "to abuse"],
  "answer": "to incite people"
},
{
  "id": 341,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The slope of the line passing through (a,b) and \( \frac{1}{a} \) is:",
  "options": ["0", "4", "3", "2"],
  "answer": "0"
},
{
  "id": 342,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If P(AUB)=1, two events a and b are",
  "options": ["mutually exclusive", "equally likely events", "exhaustive events", "dependent events"],
  "answer": "exhaustive events"
},
{
  "id": 343,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The set \(\{x: x^2 + x + 1 = 0, x \in R\}\) is:",
  "options": ["\(\{1, \sqrt{3}\}\)", "\(\{-1, \sqrt{3}\}\)", "\(\{\}\)", "\(\{-1, 0\}\)"],
  "answer": "\(\{\}\)"
},
{
  "id": 344,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Every rational number is also",
  "options": ["natural number", "a whole number", "an integer number", "a real number"],
  "answer": "a real number"
},
{
  "id": 345,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( f(u) = \frac{u}{u-1} \), then \( \frac{f(a)}{f(a+1)} \) is:",
  "options": ["\( f(-a) \)", "\( f(\frac{1}{a}) \)", "\( f(a^2) \)", "\( f(\frac{-a}{a+1}) \)"],
  "answer": "\( f(a^2) \)"
},
{
  "id": 346,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the first term of an AP is 2 and the common difference is 4. The sum of its 40 terms is:",
  "options": ["3200", "1600", "300", "1750"],
  "answer": "3200"
},
{
  "id": 347,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of cot 30° is:",
  "options": ["\(\frac{2}{\sqrt{3}}\)", "\(\frac{2}{\sqrt{3}}\)", "\(\sqrt{3}\)", "1"],
  "answer": "\(\sqrt{3}\)"
},
{
  "id": 348,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If AB=C exists, which of the following order of matrices is possible?",
  "options": ["\( A_2 x_3, B_3 x_2, C_2 x_3 \)", "\( A_3 x_2, B_2 x_3, C_3 x_2 \)", "\( A_3 x_2, B_2 x_3, C_3 x_3 \)", "\( A_3 x_3, B_2 x_3, C_3 x_3 \)"],
  "answer": "\( A_3 x_2, B_2 x_3, C_3 x_3 \)"
},
{
  "id": 349,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of 4 walls of square room is 120m². If the height is 5m, the area of its floor is",
  "options": ["56m²", "36m²", "46m²", "26m²"],
  "answer": "36m²"
},
{
  "id": 350,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "one -third of a number is 20 more than one-fifth of that number. What is the number?",
  "options": ["30", "84", "102", "150"],
  "answer": "150"
},
{
  "id": 351,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of \(\begin{vmatrix} 48 & 1 & 6 \\ 32 & 5 & 4 \\ 16 & 3 & 2 \end{vmatrix}\) is :",
  "options": ["1", "2", "0", "4"],
  "answer": "0"
},
{
  "id": 352,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Raman salary was decreased by 50% and subsequently increased by 50%. He has a loss of:",
  "options": ["0%", "25%", "0.25%", "2.5%"],
  "answer": "25%"
},
{
  "id": 353,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If a=4b, what percent of 2a is 2b?",
  "options": ["10%", "20%", "25%", "26%"],
  "answer": "25%"
},
{
  "id": 354,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "What percentage is 250 out of 1 kg?",
  "options": ["25%", "35%", "24%", "30%"],
  "answer": "25%"
},
{
  "id": 355,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The equation of the straight line passing through (2,4) and having slope -2 is:",
  "options": ["2x+y=8", "2x-y=4", "x+2y=8", "x-2y=4"],
  "answer": "2x+y=8"
},
{
  "id": 356,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A sum reckoned at 12% SI amounts to Rs.2409 in 4 years, the sum is:",
  "options": ["1625", "1635", "1640", "1652"],
  "answer": "1635"
},
{
  "id": 357,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Ram gains the cost price of 10 books by selling 50 books.His profit percentage is:",
  "options": ["30%", "25%", "20%", "16%"],
  "answer": "20%"
},
{
  "id": 358,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The cost price of 12 articles is equal to the selling price of 9 articles, the profit percent is",
  "options": ["33.33%", "40.5%", "45%", "49%"],
  "answer": "33.33%"
},
{
  "id": 359,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of a triangular field whose three sides are 300,400 and 500m (in m²) is:",
  "options": ["6000", "5000", "400", "200"],
  "answer": "6000"
},
{
  "id": 360,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The number of bricks, each 4cm×3cm×2cm are required to construct a wall having the dimension 11cm×96cm×64cm is:",
  "options": ["281500", "281600", "218500", "2185"],
  "answer": "281600"
},
{
  "id": 361,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The selling price of 20 articles is equal to the cost price of 20 articles. The gain percentage is",
  "options": ["25%", "50%", "60%", "70%"],
  "answer": "0%"
},
{
  "id": 362,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of sec\(60^\circ\) is:",
  "options": ["\(\frac{1}{2}\)", "\(\frac{\sqrt{3}}{2}\)", "2", "\(\frac{1}{\sqrt{3}}\)"],
  "answer": "2"
},
{
  "id": 363,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The rate percent per annum that a sum of money trebles itself in 25 years is:",
  "options": ["25%", "10%", "4%", "8%"],
  "answer": "8%"
},
{
  "id": 364,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The present age of mother and her daughter are 30 years and 14 years respectively. the number of years ago that the product of their age was 192 is:",
  "options": ["5", "6", "7", "9"],
  "answer": "6"
},
{
  "id": 365,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If 5 is subtracted from the square of a number and the result is 20, the number is:",
  "options": ["\(\pm 5\)", "\(\pm 6\)", "\(\pm 7\)", "\(\pm 9\)"],
  "answer": "\(\pm 5\)"
},
{
  "id": 366,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A rope is 40 ft. long is cut into two pieces. If one piece is 18 ft. longer than the other. What is the length, in feet, of the shorter piece?",
  "options": ["11", "12", "13", "14"],
  "answer": "11"
},
{
  "id": 367,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(M = \begin{pmatrix} 1 & 2 \\ 2 & 3 \end{pmatrix}\), \(M^2 - nM - 1 = 0\), the value of \(n\) is:",
  "options": ["-2", "-4", "4", "2"],
  "answer": "4"
},
{
  "id": 368,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The inequality \(-7 \leq 2x + 5 \leq 7\) is equivalent to:",
  "options": ["-6 \(\leq x \leq 1\)", "-6 \(\leq x \leq 1\)", "-7 \(\leq x \leq 5\)", "-6 \(\leq x \leq 1\)"],
  "answer": "-6 \(\leq x \leq 1\)"
},
{
  "id": 369,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(f(x) = 3x + 5\), the value of \(\frac{f(x + h) - f(x)}{h}\) is:",
  "options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
  "answer": "3"
},
{
  "id": 370,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The difference of two irrational numbers is:",
  "options": ["always an irrational number", "always a rational number", "always a real number", "All of the above"],
  "answer": "always a real number"
},
{
  "id": 371,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If p-q+r=4 and p+q+r=8, the value of p+r=",
  "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"],
  "answer": "6"
},
{
  "id": 372,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(\frac{a}{4} = \frac{b}{5} = \text{then}, \frac{a+b+c}{c}\) is",
  "options": ["4", "2", "7", "none"],
  "answer": "none"
},
{
  "id": 373,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If 60% of 450=15x, the value of x is:",
  "options": ["6", "18", "36", "72"],
  "answer": "18"
},
{
  "id": 374,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The system of equation -4x+6y+2z=8 and 2x-3y-z=-14 have:",
  "options": ["unique solution", "no solution", "infinitely many solutions", "none of these"],
  "answer": "no solution"
},
{
  "id": 375,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of rectangular field is 493m² and its perimeter is 92 meter. the length and breadth(in m) are:",
  "options": ["7,4", "9,7", "29,17", "19,13"],
  "answer": "29,17"
},
{
  "id": 376,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "While solving the value of x is \(x^3\)-\(3x^2\)+\(3x\)-1=0",
  "options": ["2", "1", "both", "none"],
  "answer": "1"
},
{
  "id": 377,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The sides of a triangle are 3cm, 4cm and 5cm. it is:",
  "options": ["a right-angled triangle", "an isosceles triangle", "an equilateral triangle", "none of these"],
  "answer": "a right-angled triangle"
},
{
  "id": 378,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Which of the following represents all solutions of the inequality \(x^2<2x\)?",
  "options": ["-1<x<1", "1<x<3", "0<x<2", "4<x<6"],
  "answer": "0<x<2"
},
{
  "id": 379,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the terms 2x,x+10 and 3x+2 be in AP, the value of x is",
  "options": ["7", "10", "6", "5"],
  "answer": "6"
},
{
  "id": 380,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If t_n=3n-2, the value of S_5 is:",
  "options": ["35", "40", "45", "50"],
  "answer": "35"
},
{
  "id": 381,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( S_n = 1 + 2 + 3 + \ldots + n = 20 \) the sum of the series \( S_n = 1^3 + 2^3 + 3^3 + \ldots + n^3 \) is:",
  "options": ["400", "500", "450", "1000"],
  "answer": "400"
},
{
  "id": 382,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "While selling a pen for Rs.50, there is a loss of 5%, for what price should it be sold to gain 5%?",
  "options": ["55.26", "52.63", "55", "56.32"],
  "answer": "55.26"
},
{
  "id": 383,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A man sold 250 chairs and had gain equal to the selling price of 50 chairs. His profit percent is:",
  "options": ["5%", "10%", "25%", "50%"],
  "answer": "25%"
},
{
  "id": 384,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A watch is bought at Rs.250 and sold at Rs.300, the gain percentage is:",
  "options": ["25%", "20%", "50%", "none"],
  "answer": "20%"
},
{
  "id": 385,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The list price of an article is 25% above the selling price and cost price is 40% below the list price, then rate of discount is:",
  "options": ["15%", "20%", "25%", "40%"],
  "answer": "20%"
},
{
  "id": 386,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( A = \begin{pmatrix} n & 0 \\ 0 & 1 \end{pmatrix} \) and \( A^2 \) is identity matrix, the value of \( n \) is:",
  "options": ["1", "2", "0", "3"],
  "answer": "1"
},
{
  "id": 387,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( P = \begin{pmatrix} 1 & 2 \\ 3 & -4 \end{pmatrix}, Q = \begin{pmatrix} x & 3 \\ 2 & -1 \end{pmatrix} \), determinant of \( 2p - 3Q \) is -5, the value of \( x \) is equal to:",
  "options": ["-1/2", "1/2", "-1/3", "-1/4"],
  "answer": "-1/2"
},
{
  "id": 388,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The simple interest on Rs.1250 for 5 years at 8% p.a is:",
  "options": ["480", "1000", "500", "625"],
  "answer": "500"
},
{
  "id": 389,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If a sum of money doubles itself in 8 years at simple interest, the rate percent per annum is:",
  "options": ["10.5%", "11.5%", "12.5%", "13.5%"],
  "answer": "12.5%"
},
{
  "id": 390,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If two numbers are in the ratio 5:7 and their least common multiple is 315, their product is:",
  "options": ["2385", "2538", "2358", "2835"],
  "answer": "2835"
},
{
  "id": 391,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The famous Halesi mahadev temple is situated in:",
  "options": ["Taplejung", "Khotang", "Sarlahi", "Morang"],
  "answer": "Khotang"
},
{
  "id": 392,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The oldest flag in the world is of:",
  "options": ["Italy", "Russia", "Denmark", "China"],
  "answer": "Denmark"
},
{
  "id": 393,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The Guitar was firstly introduced from:",
  "options": ["Spain", "Germany", "France", "America"],
  "answer": "Spain"
},
{
  "id": 394,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "In computer abbreviation of AI usually means?",
  "options": ["Art Info", "Artificial Intelligence", "Artificial interest", "Artificial Internet"],
  "answer": "Artificial Intelligence"
},
{
  "id": 395,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Who is the current vice chancellor of the Tribhuvan University?",
  "options": ["Dilli Pd. Sapkota", "Shivalal Bhusal", "Ram pd. Khatiwada", "Tirtha Khaniya"],
  "answer": "Tirtha Khaniya"
},
{
  "id": 396,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The national game of Bhutan is:",
  "options": ["Cricket", "Archery", "Bull fighting", "Football"],
  "answer": "Archery"
},
{
  "id": 397,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The CEO of Apple is:",
  "options": ["Satya Nadela", "Tim Cook", "Warren Buffet", "Sundar Pichai"],
  "answer": "Tim Cook"
},
{
  "id": 398,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?",
  "options": ["Brasilia", "Rio de Janeiro", "São paulo", "Salvador"],
  "answer": "Brasilia"
},
{
  "id": 399,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Who is the captain of Nepal's National Football team?",
  "options": ["Anil gurung", "Bimal Gharti", "Bharat Khawas", "Biraj Maharjan"],
  "answer": "Biraj Maharjan"
},
{
  "id": 400,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Which country is known as 'the Gift of Nile'?",
  "options": ["Iraq", "Iran", "Egypt", "Italy"],
  "answer": "Egypt"
},
{
  "id": 401,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "An apple of discord",
  "options": ["cause of wealth", "cause of illness", "cause of happiness", "cause of quarrel"],
  "answer": "cause of quarrel"
},
{
  "id": 402,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Cut both hands",
  "options": ["very big loss", "very hard worker", "in favor of both sides", "against both sides"],
  "answer": "in favor of both sides"
},
{
  "id": 403,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Roots and branch",
  "options": ["entirely", "step by step", "part by part", "bare truth"],
  "answer": "entirely"
},
{
  "id": 404,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "A seminar is generally form of......interaction.",
  "options": ["academic", "social", "formal", "artificial"],
  "answer": "academic"
},
{
  "id": 405,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "An archaeologist studies about the......of human.",
  "options": ["rock", "history", "past", "future"],
  "answer": "past"
},
{
  "id": 406,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Back of beyond.",
  "options": ["an ideal place for holidays", "place with certain memories", "a religious place", "a lonely forsaken place"],
  "answer": "a lonely forsaken place"
},
{
  "id": 407,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Eat humble pie.",
  "options": ["to forgive", "to apologize", "to request", "to order"],
  "answer": "to apologize"
},
{
  "id": 408,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The synonym of \"SUMMIT\" is:",
  "options": ["base", "slope", "declivity", "peak"],
  "answer": "peak"
},
{
  "id": 409,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"FACULTY\"?",
  "options": ["privilege", "desire", "branch", "ability"],
  "answer": "ability"
},
{
  "id": 410,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"RECTIFY\".",
  "options": ["to command", "to correct", "to destroy", "to build"],
  "answer": "to correct"
},
{
  "id": 411,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The antonym of \"CONFESS\" is:",
  "options": ["deny", "refuse", "contest", "contend"],
  "answer": "deny"
},
{
  "id": 412,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give the antonym of \"FICKLE\".",
  "options": ["steadfast", "independent", "unwise", "esoteric"],
  "answer": "steadfast"
},
{
  "id": 413,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "What is the antonym of \"BASE\"?",
  "options": ["roof", "height", "top", "climax"],
  "answer": "top"
},
{
  "id": 414,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The meaning of \"palette\" is:",
  "options": ["artist's brush keeping box", "artist's paint mixing board", "artist's frame box", "artist's planning board"],
  "answer": "artist's paint mixing board"
},
{
  "id": 415,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The word \"Saturated\" gives the meaning as:",
  "options": ["drenched", "soaked", "full of", "all"],
  "answer": "all"
},
{
  "id": 416,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Knowledge is like a deep well fed by......springs, and your mind is the little bucket that you drop in it.",
  "options": ["perennial", "eternal", "sterling", "immortal"],
  "answer": "perennial"
},
{
  "id": 417,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "It was through to the second world war that Russia......herself increased......in power, wealth and prestige.",
  "options": ["saw, abundantly", "notice, guiltily", "witnessed, prodigiously", "none of these"],
  "answer": "witnessed, prodigiously"
},
{
  "id": 418,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Those who seek......from others must learn to forgive and forget.",
  "options": ["leniency", "clemency", "courtesy", "retribution"],
  "answer": "leniency"
},
{
  "id": 419,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "His......of the topic was so good that students had few doubts to raise at the end.",
  "options": ["exposure", "clarity", "exposition", "picturization"],
  "answer": "exposition"
},
{
  "id": 420,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The accused was released on pending hearing of his case.",
  "options": ["bale", "deposit", "bail", "bond"],
  "answer": "bail"
},
{
  "id": 421,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He was killed......a highway man......a dagger.",
  "options": ["by; with", "with; for", "by; for", "in; for"],
  "answer": "by; with"
},
{
  "id": 422,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Pakistan is not enamored......the bomb for its own sake.",
  "options": ["of", "for", "with", "by"],
  "answer": "of"
},
{
  "id": 423,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He dispensed with the services......his honest clerk.",
  "options": ["for", "by", "of", "to"],
  "answer": "of"
},
{
  "id": 424,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The teacher has no control......the students.",
  "options": ["with", "at", "over", "on"],
  "answer": "over"
},
{
  "id": 425,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "There is no hinderance......his going there.",
  "options": ["to", "on", "over", "at"],
  "answer": "to"
},
{
  "id": 426,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I have a bistate......publicity.",
  "options": ["about", "at", "against", "for"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 427,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "My cousin has invested a lot of money......farming.",
  "options": ["in", "for", "onto", "on"],
  "answer": "in"
},
{
  "id": 428,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Plants absorb moisture......the air.",
  "options": ["for", "in", "from", "to"],
  "answer": "from"
},
{
  "id": 429,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "It is vain to calculate......an uncertain result.",
  "options": ["upon", "over", "into", "for"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 430,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Jagdish had no servant to attend......him.",
  "options": ["upon", "over", "with", "to"],
  "answer": "to"
},
{
  "id": 431,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The word 'quest' is meant for:",
  "options": ["to seek", "to look for", "to search", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "all of the above"
},
{
  "id": 432,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Go to the dogs.",
  "options": ["to be ruined", "to be in danger", "to take risk", "to disobey elders"],
  "answer": "to be ruined"
},
{
  "id": 433,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Keen is meant to:",
  "options": ["very clean", "very warm", "very dull", "very sensitive"],
  "answer": "very sensitive"
},
{
  "id": 434,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Well disposed to",
  "options": ["useless", "help to somebody", "very much excited", "to be settle for less"],
  "answer": "help to somebody"
},
{
  "id": 435,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Pay lip service.",
  "options": ["false appreciation", "pretend to regard", "true relation", "false commitment"],
  "answer": "pretend to regard"
},
{
  "id": 436,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Get on",
  "options": ["to step down", "to step up", "to help", "to think"],
  "answer": "to step up"
},
{
  "id": 437,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The slope of a vertical line is:",
  "options": ["0", "more than 0", "not defined", "none of these"],
  "answer": "not defined"
},
{
  "id": 438,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( P(A \cap B) = 0 \), two events are:",
  "options": ["mutually exclusive", "equally like events", "exhaustive events", "dependent events"],
  "answer": "mutually exclusive"
},
{
  "id": 439,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Which of the following is the true statement?",
  "options": ["0 ∈ {}", "0 ∈ {0}", "0 ∈ {1}", "0 ⊂ {0}"],
  "answer": "0 ∈ {0}"
},
{
  "id": 440,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Each prime number has:",
  "options": ["no factor", "only one factor", "only two factors", "more than two factors"],
  "answer": "only two factors"
},
{
  "id": 441,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the function \( f(x) = 2x^2 - 5x + 2 \), then the value of \( \frac{f(4+h) - f(4)}{h} \) is:",
  "options": ["11-2h", "11+2h", "2h-11", "none of these"],
  "answer": "11+2h"
},
{
  "id": 442,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the sum of three terms of an A.P is 51 and product of last and first term is 273, the numbers are:",
  "options": ["21,15,13", "21,17,13", "19,17,13", "19,15,13"],
  "answer": "21,17,13"
},
{
  "id": 443,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of cosec 60\(^\circ\) is:",
  "options": ["\(\frac{2}{\sqrt{3}}\)", "\(\frac{2}{\sqrt{3}}\)", "\(\sqrt{3}\)", "1"],
  "answer": "\(\frac{2}{\sqrt{3}}\)"
},
{
  "id": 444,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( A = (aij)_{m \times n} \) and \( B = (aij)_{m \times n} \) be any two matrices and A+B id defined, the order of (A+B) is:",
  "options": ["\( m \times n \)", "\( n \times m \)", "\( m \times m \)", "\( n \times n \)"],
  "answer": "\( m \times n \)"
},
{
  "id": 445,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of the four wall, ceiling and floor of a room is 56m\(^2\). If the room is 3m long and 2m wide, the height of room is:",
  "options": ["4.9m", "5m", "4.7m", "4.4m"],
  "answer": "4.4m"
},
{
  "id": 446,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "One half of a number is 17 more than one-third of that number. What is the number?",
  "options": ["52", "84", "102", "112"],
  "answer": "102"
},
{
  "id": 447,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Two numbers are respectively 20% and 50% more than the third number. What % is the first number of the second?",
  "options": ["40%", "50%", "80%", "70%"],
  "answer": "80%"
},
{
  "id": 448,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Hari spent Rs.25, which is 15% of his monthly wage. His monthly wage is:",
  "options": ["Rs.80", "Rs.166\(\frac{2}{3}\)", "Rs.225", "Rs312.5"],
  "answer": "Rs.166\(\frac{2}{3}\)"
},
{
  "id": 449,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If 15% of a number is 4.5, then,45% of the same number is:",
  "options": ["1.5", "3.5", "13.5", "15"],
  "answer": "13.5"
},
{
  "id": 450,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Which one is perpendicular to line 2x+3y=4?",
  "options": ["2x-3y=5", "2x-3y+7=0", "3x+2y=8", "3x-2y+7=0"],
  "answer": "3x-2y+7=0"
},
{
  "id": 451,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The interest on a sum of money of 6% for 2.5 years is Rs.270, the amount is",
  "options": ["4000", "2070", "4100", "4150"],
  "answer": "2070"
},
{
  "id": 452,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A man gains the selling price of 5 books by selling 25 books. the percentage gain is",
  "options": ["20%", "25%", "25.5%", "15%"],
  "answer": "20%"
},
{
  "id": 453,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "I lost 7% by selling an article for Rs.139.50. At what price must I have sold it to have 10% gain?",
  "options": ["15.0", "16.5", "17.5", "20.0"],
  "answer": "16.5"
},
{
  "id": 454,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Two sides of a right-angled triangle are 12cm and 13cm.The length of third side of right-angled triangle is",
  "options": ["5 units", "11 units", "12 units", "56 units"],
  "answer": "5 units"
},
{
  "id": 455,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The volume of a wall which is built by using 3000 bricks having the dimension \( 14\text{cm} \times 10\text{cm} \times 6\text{cm} \) is:",
  "options": ["\( 2.52\text{m}^3 \)", "\( 2.25\text{m}^3 \)", "\( 3.25\text{m}^3 \)", "\( 3.52\text{m}^3 \)"],
  "answer": "\( 2.52\text{m}^3 \)"
},
{
  "id": 456,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A vendor lemon at 6 for a rupee, how many for a rupee must be sold to gain 20%?",
  "options": ["5", "6", "8", "9"],
  "answer": "5"
},
{
  "id": 457,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of sec55\(^0\) is:",
  "options": ["\(\frac{\sqrt{2}}{2}\)", "\(\frac{\sqrt{3}}{2}\)", "\(\sqrt{2}\)", "\(\frac{1}{\sqrt{3}}\)"],
  "answer": "\(\sqrt{2}\)"
},
{
  "id": 458,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The interest on a sum of money is \( 3/11 \) of the amounts in 3yrs.The rate of interest is:",
  "options": ["\( 13.5\% \)", "\( 13\% \)", "\( 12.5\% \)", "\( 12\% \)"],
  "answer": "\( 12.5\% \)"
},
{
  "id": 459,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Jack is now 14 years older than Bill. If in 10 years Jack will be twice as old as Bill, how old will Jack be in 5 years?",
  "options": ["21", "23", "25", "27"],
  "answer": "23"
},
{
  "id": 460,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If 2 is subtracted from the square of a number and the result is 7, the number is:",
  "options": ["\(\pm 3\)", "\(\pm 4\)", "\(\pm 5\)", "\(\pm 6\)"],
  "answer": "\(\pm 3\)"
},
{
  "id": 461,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the area of the square region having sides of length 6cm is equal to the area of rectangular region having width 2.5cm, then the length of the rectangle (in cm) is:",
  "options": ["8.5", "12", "13", "14.4"],
  "answer": "14.4"
},
{
  "id": 462,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The solution of the set of equations \( x-y=2 \) & \( 2x+3y=9 \) is:",
  "options": ["1,3", "2,1", "3,2", "3,1"],
  "answer": "3,1"
},
{
  "id": 463,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The interval satisfying \( 3 \leq x - 1 \leq 5 \) is:",
  "options": ["[3,5]", "[4,6]", "[2,3]", "(2,3)"],
  "answer": "[4,6]"
},
{
  "id": 464,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The constant function is a:",
  "options": ["one to one", "onto", "into", "objective"],
  "answer": "into"
},
{
  "id": 465,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of \((2+\sqrt{3})(2-\sqrt{3})(3+\sqrt{5})(3-\sqrt{5})\) is:",
  "options": ["rational number", "irrational number", "An imaginary number", "All of above"],
  "answer": "rational number"
},
{
  "id": 466,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(x+y=4c/5\), \(y+z=7c/5\) and \(z+x=9c/5\), the value of \(x+y+z\) is:",
  "options": ["\(7c/15\)", "\(c\)", "\(2c\)", "\(3c\)"],
  "answer": "\(2c\)"
},
{
  "id": 467,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Divide of Rs.750 into three parts in the ratio 4:5:6 are:",
  "options": ["200,250,300", "250,250,250", "350,250,150", "400,500,600"],
  "answer": "200,250,300"
},
{
  "id": 468,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The ratio 5:4 expressed as percent equals to:",
  "options": ["125%", "80%", "40%", "60%"],
  "answer": "125%"
},
{
  "id": 469,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(1+\frac{1}{x}=2\frac{2}{x}\), the value of \(x\) is",
  "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
  "answer": "1"
},
{
  "id": 470,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of rectangular courtyard is \(63m^2\) and perimeter is \(32m\).the length and breadth (in m) are:",
  "options": ["4,3", "9,7", "29,17", "19,13"],
  "answer": "9,7"
},
{
  "id": 471,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(\frac{1}{x+4}+\frac{1}{x+1}=\frac{1}{x}\), then \(x\) could be",
  "options": ["\(\pm 1\)", "\(\pm 2\)", "-2", "-4"],
  "answer": "-2"
},
{
  "id": 472,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Three sides of the triangle are in the ratio 1:2:3, it is:",
  "options": ["a right-angled triangle", "an isosceles triangle", "an equilateral triangle", "none of these"],
  "answer": "a right-angled triangle"
},
{
  "id": 473,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(x\) is an integer and \(y=-2x-8\), what is the least value of \(x\) for which \(y\) is less than 9?",
  "options": ["-9", "-8", "-7", "-6"],
  "answer": "-8"
},
{
  "id": 474,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The sum of the series 24,3,8,1,2,7 up to 8th term is:",
  "options": ["57", "\( 36 \frac{13}{50} \)", "\( 36 \frac{1}{9} \)", "\( 37 \frac{5}{9} \)"],
  "answer": "57"
},
{
  "id": 475,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( t_n = 2n^2 + 3n \), the value of \( S_4 \) is:",
  "options": ["90", "85", "80", "none"],
  "answer": "85"
},
{
  "id": 476,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the nth term of the series 3,10,17…… and 63,65,67…… are equal, the value of n is:",
  "options": ["8", "10", "12", "13"],
  "answer": "13"
},
{
  "id": 477,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the cost price of 18 pens and selling price of 20 pens are equal. The loss percentage is:",
  "options": ["10.5%", "10%", "11.11%", "13%"],
  "answer": "10%"
},
{
  "id": 478,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A person incurs a loss of 10% by selling a toy for Rs.10.80. At what price he should sell it to earn a profit of 20%?",
  "options": ["12", "12.96", "14.4", "none"],
  "answer": "14.4"
},
{
  "id": 479,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A machine was bought for Rs.7540 and sold at a profit of 20%, the selling price was",
  "options": ["9048", "9049", "9050", "9051"],
  "answer": "9048"
},
{
  "id": 480,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A 30% discount reduces the price of a commodity by Rs.90. If the discount is reduced to 20% then the price of the commodity will be:",
  "options": ["Rs.180", "Rs.210", "Rs.240", "Rs.300"],
  "answer": "Rs.240"
},
{
  "id": 481,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \( A = \frac{2}{-5} \) , the value of \( A - I \) is :",
  "options": ["A", "1/3 A", "1/19 A", "19"],
  "answer": "1/19 A"
},
{
  "id": 482,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of \[\begin{bmatrix} a - 6 & 2a \\ -2b & a - 6 \end{bmatrix}\] equals to",
  "options": ["a+6", "a-6", "(a+6)^2", "b+a+1"],
  "answer": "(a+6)^2"
},
{
  "id": 483,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The simple interest on Rs.400 for 1 year at 5% p.a is:",
  "options": ["20", "25", "16", "none"],
  "answer": "20"
},
{
  "id": 484,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The sum of money at the rate of 5% p.a will yield an interest of Rs.120 in 3 years is:",
  "options": ["800", "900", "1000", "1100"],
  "answer": "800"
},
{
  "id": 485,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If a:b=2:3,b:c=5:7,the value of a:b:c is",
  "options": ["2:3:7", "2:5:7", "10:15:21", "2:15:7"],
  "answer": "10:15:21"
},
{
  "id": 486,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The famous Bulbul lake is situated in:",
  "options": ["Gorkha", "Chitwan", "Tanahun", "Surkhet"],
  "answer": "Surkhet"
},
{
  "id": 487,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The oldest country in the world is:",
  "options": ["Vatican City", "Libya", "San marino", "Denmark"],
  "answer": "San marino"
},
{
  "id": 488,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The first daily newspaper of the world is",
  "options": ["The Morning Post", "Sunday Times", "The New York Times", "Daily mail"],
  "answer": "The Morning Post"
},
{
  "id": 489,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "In computer abbreviation of CAD usually means?",
  "options": ["Computer Additional Disk", "Computer Aided Data", "Computer Aided Design", "Computer Assist Design"],
  "answer": "Computer Aided Design"
},
{
  "id": 490,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Who is the current secretary general of the UN?",
  "options": ["Wan ki Moon", "U thant", "Antonio Guterres", "Kofi Annan"],
  "answer": "Antonio Guterres"
},
{
  "id": 491,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The national game of Nepal is:",
  "options": ["Cricket", "Volleyball", "Kabaddi", "Football"],
  "answer": "Volleyball"
},
{
  "id": 492,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The CEO of Google is:",
  "options": ["Satya Nadella", "Jeff Bezos", "Warren Buffet", "Sundar Pichai"],
  "answer": "Sundar Pichai"
},
{
  "id": 493,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "What is the capital of Canada?",
  "options": ["Ottawa", "Canberra", "Vancouver", "Winnipeg"],
  "answer": "Ottawa"
},
{
  "id": 494,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Logarithm tables were invented by:",
  "options": ["Blaise Pascal", "John Napier", "Charles Babbage", "John Douglas"],
  "answer": "John Napier"
},
{
  "id": 495,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Who is known as the father of the Internet?",
  "options": ["Lawrence Roberts", "Ray Tomlinson", "Vint Cerf", "Tim Berners-Lee"],
  "answer": "Vint Cerf"
},
{
  "id": 501,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "To get into hot water.",
  "options": ["Bath in the winter months", "to get healthy", "to get rich", "to get into trouble"],
  "answer": "to get into trouble"
},
{
  "id": 502,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I cannot wait to ………from the city.",
  "options": ["get away", "get in", "get out", "go on"],
  "answer": "get away"
},
{
  "id": 503,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Sorry I interrupted, ………talking.",
  "options": ["carry out", "carry on", "carry in", "carry of"],
  "answer": "carry on"
},
{
  "id": 504,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Maria ………as a bit bossy.",
  "options": ["came off", "came down", "came across", "came on"],
  "answer": "came across"
},
{
  "id": 505,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We finally………a solution to the problem.",
  "options": ["came out of", "came in of", "came up of", "came on of"],
  "answer": "came up of"
},
{
  "id": 506,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We're not together anymore, but we………great.",
  "options": ["get out", "get along", "get across", "get in"],
  "answer": "get along"
},
{
  "id": 507,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "As always, Janny………late.",
  "options": ["turned down", "turned of", "turned in", "turned up"],
  "answer": "turned up"
},
{
  "id": 508,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The synonym of \"WISE\" is:",
  "options": ["momentous", "pragmatic", "judicious", "delay"],
  "answer": "judicious"
},
{
  "id": 509,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"WEARY\"?",
  "options": ["sad", "fatigued", "sentimental", "emotional"],
  "answer": "fatigued"
},
{
  "id": 510,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"BLAND\".",
  "options": ["unpleasant", "irritating", "affable", "tasteless"],
  "answer": "tasteless"
},
{
  "id": 511,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The antonym of \"HINDER\" is:",
  "options": ["expedite", "protect", "devote", "create"],
  "answer": "expedite"
},
{
  "id": 512,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Basketball is played on court as Golf is played on:",
  "options": ["Ring", "course", "Diamond", "Field"],
  "answer": "course"
},
{
  "id": 513,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Beauty is to ugliness as adversity is to………",
  "options": ["misery", "cowardice", "happiness", "prosperity"],
  "answer": "prosperity"
},
{
  "id": 514,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "This legend has been ………from father to son.",
  "options": ["handed out", "handed down", "handed over", "handed in"],
  "answer": "handed down"
},
{
  "id": 515,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "All of us should abide………the laws of our country.",
  "options": ["on", "to", "in", "by"],
  "answer": "by"
},
{
  "id": 516,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The accused ………having made any statement.",
  "options": ["refused", "rejected", "declaimed", "denied"],
  "answer": "denied"
},
{
  "id": 517,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The opposite of \"Boost\" is:",
  "options": ["hinder", "obstruct", "discourage", "rebuke"],
  "answer": "hinder"
},
{
  "id": 518,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "No sooner did he………me………..he tried to run.",
  "options": ["notice, when", "see, then", "observe, soon", "watch, that"],
  "answer": "see, then"
},
{
  "id": 519,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We had a wonderful view of the bay through the ………",
  "options": ["window", "Zenith", "vicinity", "proximity"],
  "answer": "window"
},
{
  "id": 520,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The old man suffered………a heart attack.",
  "options": ["of", "from", "to", "with"],
  "answer": "from"
},
{
  "id": 521,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Her next birthday is the great community.",
  "options": ["of", "from", "at", "for"],
  "answer": "at"
},
{
  "id": 522,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He is responsible ……… what he does.",
  "options": ["at", "by", "from", "for"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 523,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I haven't seen her ……… five years.",
  "options": ["for", "since", "in", "none of these"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 524,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "You look good………that dress.",
  "options": ["in", "on", "no preposition", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "in"
},
{
  "id": 525,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He sits ………the computer all day.",
  "options": ["in front of", "until", "before", "none of these"],
  "answer": "in front of"
},
{
  "id": 526,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He had to repent………what he had done.",
  "options": ["of", "over", "for", "at"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 527,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Let this be an example ………the troublemakers.",
  "options": ["to", "about", "for", "against"],
  "answer": "to"
},
{
  "id": 528,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "To draw a line.",
  "options": ["To impose certain restrictions", "To restart", "To have a fair game", "To decide evenly"],
  "answer": "To impose certain restrictions"
},
{
  "id": 529,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The new owners of the paper changed the ......completely.",
  "options": ["layout", "outlook", "outlay", "outlet"],
  "answer": "layout"
},
{
  "id": 530,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Lost in the clouds.",
  "options": ["to enjoy", "to wait", "confused", "very much sure"],
  "answer": "confused"
},
{
  "id": 531,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Hang Fire.",
  "options": ["in anger", "calm", "solved issue", "unresolved issue"],
  "answer": "unresolved issue"
},
{
  "id": 532,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "By hook or by crook.",
  "options": ["by permission", "by any means", "by noble means", "by request"],
  "answer": "by any means"
},
{
  "id": 533,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "At sixes and sevens.",
  "options": ["in perfect order", "very happy", "in disorder", "very sad"],
  "answer": "in disorder"
},
{
  "id": 534,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Die hard.",
  "options": ["very weak", "about to die", "living life full", "persistent in struggle"],
  "answer": "persistent in struggle"
},
{
  "id": 535,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He ………to us for half an hour.",
  "options": ["said", "spoke", "talked", "told"],
  "answer": "spoke"
},

{
  "id": 540,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The slope of the straight line \( 4y+2x=5 \) is:",
  "options": ["-2", "\( 5/2 \)", "\( \frac{1}{2} \)", "\( -\frac{1}{2} \)"],
  "answer": "\( -\frac{1}{2} \)"
},
{
  "id": 541,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "What is the probability of death?",
  "options": ["\( 1 \)", "\( \frac{1}{2} \)", "\( 0 \)", "\( \infty \)"],
  "answer": "\( 1 \)"
},
{
  "id": 542,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The minimum value of \( n(A\cap B) \) when \( n(U)=120,  n(A)=90,  n(B)=55 \) is:",
  "options": ["40", "25", "30", "35"],
  "answer": "25"
},
{
  "id": 543,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "For any two real numbers is \( x \) and then \( |x+y| \) is",
  "options": ["equals to \( |x|+|y| \)", "less than \( |x|+|y| \)", "equals to \( x+y \)", "less than or equal to \( |x| \)"],
  "answer": "less than or equal to \( |x| \)"
},
{
  "id": 544,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the function \( f(x)=3-x^2 \), then \( f(x) \) is:",
  "options": ["even function", "periodic function", "odd function", "none of these"],
  "answer": "even function"
},
{
  "id": 545,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The nth term of the series \( 1+x+x^2+\ldots \ldots \) n terms is: (x<0)",
  "options": ["\(\frac{1-x}{1-x}\)", "\(\frac{1-x}{x-1}\)", "\(\frac{1-x}{1-x}\)", "\(\frac{x}{x-1}\)"],
  "answer": "\(\frac{1-x}{1-x}\)"
},
{
  "id": 546,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of cos180\(^\circ\) is equal to:",
  "options": ["1", "-1", "0", "∞"],
  "answer": "-1"
},
{
  "id": 547,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A and B are square matrices of same order such that AB=A and BA=BA is:",
  "options": ["diagonal matrix", "idempotent matrix", "null matrix", "symmetric matrix"],
  "answer": "idempotent matrix"
},
{
  "id": 548,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "What is the surface area of a cube whose volume os 64?",
  "options": ["16", "64", "96", "128"],
  "answer": "96"
},
{
  "id": 549,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of \(\sqrt{(31-6)(16-9)}\) equals to:",
  "options": ["5", "10", "25", "30"],
  "answer": "25"
},
{
  "id": 550,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A is a matrix of order 3×2, then each column of A contains:",
  "options": ["2 elements", "6 elements", "3 elements", "none of these"],
  "answer": "3 elements"
},
{
  "id": 551,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "10 is what % of B?",
  "options": ["10B%", "10/n%", "100/n %", "none"],
  "answer": "10B%"
},
{
  "id": 552,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The cost of 1 liter of petrol is Rs.80. The cost is increased by 30%, what will be the cost of 8 liters petrol?",
  "options": ["834", "832", "330", "none"],
  "answer": "832"
},
{
  "id": 553,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the angles of a triangle are at a ratio of 2:3:4, the greatest angle of the triangle is:",
  "options": ["70", "80", "90", "none"],
  "answer": "80"
},
{
  "id": 554,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The sum of money if it is compounded annually in rate of 5% for 2 years amounts to be Rs.44100 is:",
  "options": ["50000", "40000", "45000", "55000"],
  "answer": "40000"
},
{
  "id": 555,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the selling price of Rs.24 results in a 20% discount off the list price, the selling price that would result in a 30% discount off the list price is:",
  "options": ["Rs.16", "Rs.21", "Rs.25", "Rs.31"],
  "answer": "Rs.21"
},
{
  "id": 556,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Ram buys one gross pencil for Rs. 288. He sold each for Rs.2.25. His total profit is:",
  "options": ["Rs.36", "Rs.46", "Rs.25", "Rs.63"],
  "answer": "Rs.36"
},
{
  "id": 557,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "What is the cost of fencing a rectangular field of 50m X 35m with the barbed wire running twice around it at the rate of Rs.5 per meter?",
  "options": ["Rs.1250", "Rs.1550", "Rs.1700", "Rs.2550"],
  "answer": "Rs.1700"
},
{
  "id": 558,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The area of an equilateral Triangle can be calculated from:",
  "options": ["\(\sqrt{s(s-a)(s-b)(s-c)}\)", "\(\frac{1}{2} * b * h\)", "\(\sqrt{3}/4a^2\)", "none of the above"],
  "answer": "\(\sqrt{3}/4a^2\)"
},
{
  "id": 559,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A dealer altered his trade discount from 15% to 10%, By what percent was the selling price altered?",
  "options": ["5.88%", "5.56%", "6.88%", "7%"],
  "answer": "5.88%"
},
{
  "id": 560,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Two successive discounts of 20% and 15% is equivalent to a single discount of",
  "options": ["18", "24", "32", "36"],
  "answer": "32"
},
{
  "id": 561,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The value of tan \(45^\circ\) is",
  "options": ["\(\sqrt{3}/2\)", "\(\frac{1}{2}\)", "\(\sqrt{3}\)", "1"],
  "answer": "1"
},
{
  "id": 562,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The principal that will yield an interest of Rs.540 in 15 months at 2 paisa per rupees per month is:",
  "options": ["1080", "1800", "8100", "8010"],
  "answer": "1800"
},
{
  "id": 563,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Hari will be x years old y years old from now's years ago he was:",
  "options": ["x+y+z", "x-y-z", "y-x-z", "z-y-z"],
  "answer": "x-y-z"
},
{
  "id": 564,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A number consists of two digits whose product is 21. If 36 is subtracted from the number, the digits are interchanged. The number is:",
  "options": ["73", "72", "97", "24"],
  "answer": "73"
},
{
  "id": 565,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "What is the circumference of a circle whose area is 100π?",
  "options": ["10", "20", "10π", "20π"],
  "answer": "20π"
},
{
  "id": 566,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The system of equations \(2x+3y=6\) and \(4x+6y=8\) have",
  "options": ["unique solution", "no solution", "infinitely many solutions", "none"],
  "answer": "no solution"
},
{
  "id": 567,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(|x|>2\) means:",
  "options": ["\(2<x<2\)", "\(-2<x\leq 2\)", "\(x<-2\) or \(x>2\)", "\(x>2\)"],
  "answer": "\(x<-2\) or \(x>2\)"
},
{
  "id": 568,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(f(x)=2x+3\) and \(g(x)=x^2+7\), then the value of \(x\) for which \(f[g(x)] = 25\) are",
  "options": ["\(\pm1\)", "\(\pm2\)", "\(\pm3\)", "\(\pm4\)"],
  "answer": "\(\pm3\)"
},
{
  "id": 569,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If a matrix is of order \(7 \times 5\), each column will contain",
  "options": ["5 elements", "7 elements", "6 elements", "35 elements"],
  "answer": "7 elements"
},
{
  "id": 570,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The system of equations \(2x+y=4,3x+2y=-2\) and \(x+y=-2\) have:",
  "options": ["no solution", "one solution", "two solutions", "infinitely many solution"],
  "answer": "no solution"
},
{
  "id": 571,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If A:B=5:4 and B:C=6:7, the value of A:B:C is:",
  "options": ["30:24:28", "5:24:7", "5:4:7", "5:6:7"],
  "answer": "30:24:28"
},
{
  "id": 572,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If 5:7=15:x, the value of x is:",
  "options": ["35", "27", "21", "18"],
  "answer": "21"
},
{
  "id": 573,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The sum of the reciprocals of \(\frac{1}{x^2}\) and \(\frac{1}{y^2}\) is:",
  "options": ["\(\frac{1}{x} + \frac{1}{y}\)", "\(x^2+y^2\)", "\(x^2y^2\)", "\(x^4y^4\)"],
  "answer": "\(x^2+y^2\)"
},
{
  "id": 574,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The width of a rectangle is 2cm less than its length & its length and perimeter is 12cm. the area of a rectangle is:",
  "options": ["12cm\(^2\)", "24cm\(^2\)", "18cm\(^2\)", "8 cm\(^2\)"],
  "answer": "8 cm\(^2\)"
},
{
  "id": 575,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The solution of the system of equation \(x-y=2\) & \(2x+3y=0\).",
  "options": ["1,3", "2,1", "3,2", "3,1"],
  "answer": "3,1"
},
{
  "id": 576,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The slope of the line joining through (3,2) and is perpendicular to the line that passes through (-2,3) and (2,-3) is:",
  "options": ["-3/2", "\(\frac{1}{3}\)", "\(\frac{1}{2}\)", "2"],
  "answer": "\(\frac{1}{3}\)"
},
{
  "id": 577,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(2<x<5\) and \(3<y<5\), which of the following best describes x-y?",
  "options": ["-3<x-y<2", "-3<x-y<5", "0<x-y<2", "2<x-y<5"],
  "answer": "-3<x-y<2"
},
{
  "id": 578,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The two numbers whose AM=50 & GM=16 are:",
  "options": ["20,30", "4,64", "20,50", "50,10"],
  "answer": "4,64"
},
{
  "id": 579,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If the arithmetic means between b and b+8 is 14, the value of b is:",
  "options": ["14", "15", "16", "10"],
  "answer": "10"
},
{
  "id": 580,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A shopkeeper bought lemons for Rs.5 and sold 5 for Rs.6. His profit percentage is:",
  "options": ["66%", "44%", "88%", "55%"],
  "answer": "44%"
},
{
  "id": 581,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "By selling transistor set for Rs.1150, the dealer makes profit of 25%. Is the CP of that transistor set is?",
  "options": ["Rs.880", "Rs.900", "Rs.920", "Rs.940"],
  "answer": "Rs.920"
},
{
  "id": 582,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The selling price to gain 15% profit costing a book Rs.50 is",
  "options": ["Rs.20", "Rs.50", "Rs.16", "Rs.30"],
  "answer": "Rs.50"
},
{
  "id": 583,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "An agent sells flour at Rs.22 per kg. and gets Rs.550 as a commission at 5%. The price of flour he sold is:",
  "options": ["Rs.400", "Rs.600", "Rs.500", "Rs.300"],
  "answer": "Rs.500"
},
{
  "id": 584,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If an article was sold at 20% loss with selling price Rs.800, the CP is:",
  "options": ["Rs.1000", "Rs.2000", "Rs.1500", "Rs.800"],
  "answer": "Rs.1000"
},
{
  "id": 585,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "If \(A=(aij)_m \times n\) and \(B=(ajj)_m \times n\) be any two matrices and (A+B) is defined then the order of (A+B) is:",
  "options": ["\(m \times n\)", "\(n \times m\)", "\(m \times m\)", "\(n \times n\)"],
  "answer": "\(m \times n\)"
},
{
  "id": 586,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "A book seller purchased a book at Rs.20 and sold it at a profit of 15%. The selling price in Rs. of a book would be:",
  "options": ["Rs.22", "Rs.23", "Rs.27", "none"],
  "answer": "Rs.23"
},
{
  "id": 587,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "Two successive discounts of 20% and 15% is equivalent to a single discount of",
  "options": ["18", "24", "32", "36"],
  "answer": "32"
},
{
  "id": 588,
  "type": "mathematics",
  "question": "The selling price of four articles equals to cost price of 5 articles. The gain is:",
  "options": ["20%", "25%", "28%", "30%"],
  "answer": "25%"
},
{
  "id": 589,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "In which district is a Rara lake located?",
  "options": ["Dolpa", "Mugu", "Manang", "Myagdi"],
  "answer": "Mugu"
},
{
  "id": 590,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The first president of America is:",
  "options": ["Abraham Lincoln", "George Washington", "George W. Bush", "Bill Clinton"],
  "answer": "George Washington"
},
{
  "id": 591,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Which of the following is not part of the internet?",
  "options": ["HTTP", "WWW", "CD-ROM", "Email"],
  "answer": "CD-ROM"
},
{
  "id": 592,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "How many bits is a byte?",
  "options": ["4", "6", "10", "8"],
  "answer": "8"
},
{
  "id": 593,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Bulls and bears are the term associated with:",
  "options": ["Bull fighting", "Stock exchange", "Parliamentary affairs", "Computer virus"],
  "answer": "Stock exchange"
},
{
  "id": 594,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The tech valley located in USA is namely called as:",
  "options": ["silk valley", "wool valley", "Silicon Valley", "Cotton valley"],
  "answer": "Silicon Valley"
},
{
  "id": 595,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "How many districts are there in province no. 5?",
  "options": ["10", "9", "17", "12"],
  "answer": "12"
},
{
  "id": 596,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "A website's main page is called",
  "options": ["web page", "home page", "search page", "browser page"],
  "answer": "home page"
},
{
  "id": 597,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "Who won the men's Wimbledon Championships 2018?",
  "options": ["Rafael Nadal", "Novac Djokovic", "Andy murray", "Roger Federer"],
  "answer": "Novac Djokovic"
},
{
  "id": 598,
  "type": "general_knowledge",
  "question": "The national anthem of Nepal was written by:",
  "options": ["Bairagi Kaila", "Byakul Saila", "Byakul Maila", "Ambar Gurung"],
  "answer": "Byakul Maila"
},
{
  "id": 601,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "\"Don't bring ...... the fight again, please!\"",
  "options": ["bring up", "bring down", "bring off", "bring out"],
  "answer": "bring up"
},
{
  "id": 602,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I tried to sound happy but it ...... as over-excited.",
  "options": ["came off", "came down", "came across", "came out"],
  "answer": "came across"
},
{
  "id": 603,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The thieves manage to ...... in a stolen car.",
  "options": ["get across", "get away", "get along", "get about"],
  "answer": "get away"
},
{
  "id": 604,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "I will ...... to my job until may.",
  "options": ["hold down", "hold in", "hold on", "hold up"],
  "answer": "hold on"
},
{
  "id": 605,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We ...... out in the back of his car.",
  "options": ["made out", "made at", "make up", "made in"],
  "answer": "made out"
},
{
  "id": 606,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He ...... his memories to write a book.",
  "options": ["put up", "put in", "put at", "put down"],
  "answer": "put down"
},
{
  "id": 607,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Let's ...... his number in yellow pages.",
  "options": ["look at", "look up", "look down", "look in"],
  "answer": "look up"
},
{
  "id": 608,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The synonym of \"Advice\" is:",
  "options": ["council", "counsel", "practice", "proposal"],
  "answer": "counsel"
},
{
  "id": 609,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"Harmony\"?",
  "options": ["cemetery", "Ceremony", "Symmetry", "hierarchy"],
  "answer": "Symmetry"
},
{
  "id": 610,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"Wise\".",
  "options": ["momentous", "pragmatic", "judicious", "delay"],
  "answer": "judicious"
},
{
  "id": 611,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The antonym of \"Insult\" is:",
  "options": ["humiliation", "credulity", "degradation", "honor"],
  "answer": "honor"
},
{
  "id": 612,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Give the antonym of \"Offend\".",
  "options": ["angry", "hate", "force", "respect"],
  "answer": "respect"
},
{
  "id": 613,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Killing of yourself is called………",
  "options": ["regicide", "genocide", "sororicide", "Suicide"],
  "answer": "Suicide"
},
{
  "id": 614,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Many religious beliefs in the ………….. Soul.",
  "options": ["immoral", "amoral", "immortal", "Imocal"],
  "answer": "immortal"
},
{
  "id": 615,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Football is played on a ground whereas wrestling in a ......",
  "options": ["court", "arena", "track", "pitch"],
  "answer": "arena"
},
{
  "id": 616,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The ……… document was destroyed by:",
  "options": ["factions", "facetious", "factitious", "fictitious"],
  "answer": "fictitious"
},
{
  "id": 617,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The students organized a ………",
  "options": ["fate", "feat", "feet", "fate"],
  "answer": "feat"
},
{
  "id": 618,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The opposite of \"Exotic\" is:",
  "options": ["Poor", "Expose", "Fragile", "Indigenous"],
  "answer": "Indigenous"
},
{
  "id": 619,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "We lost confidence in him because he never......the grandiose promises he made.",
  "options": ["Forgot", "Tried", "Delivered on", "Relied Upon"],
  "answer": "Delivered on"
},
{
  "id": 620,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "A referee should be......in the outcome of the match.",
  "options": ["uninterested", "disinterested", "involved", "cooperative"],
  "answer": "disinterested"
},
{
  "id": 621,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "A university is where you study......a degree.",
  "options": ["at", "by", "from", "for"],
  "answer": "for"
},
{
  "id": 622,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Who was the first man......the moon?",
  "options": ["at", "on", "in", "none of these"],
  "answer": "on"
},
{
  "id": 623,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Religious leaders should not delve......politics.",
  "options": ["with", "into", "in", "at"],
  "answer": "into"
},
{
  "id": 624,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "In the morning, I simply take a glance......the newspaper headlines.",
  "options": ["of", "at", "over", "on"],
  "answer": "at"
},
{
  "id": 625,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He was killed......a highway man......a dagger.",
  "options": ["by; with", "with; for", "by; for", "in; for"],
  "answer": "by; with"
},
{
  "id": 626,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "He has been absent......Monday.",
  "options": ["since", "for", "from", "to"],
  "answer": "since"
},
{
  "id": 627,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Shyam was no control......his temper.",
  "options": ["after", "in", "over", "at"],
  "answer": "over"
},
{
  "id": 628,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Peter's speech pointed......some of our defects.",
  "options": ["at", "towards", "to", "on"],
  "answer": "at"
},
{
  "id": 629,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Bad blood.",
  "options": ["wounded in scuffle", "bitter relations", "dishonest", "arrogant"],
  "answer": "bitter relations"
},
{
  "id": 630,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Put off.",
  "options": ["to start something", "to delay for sometime", "make victory", "go away"],
  "answer": "to delay for sometime"
},
{
  "id": 631,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Crocodile tears.",
  "options": ["true tears", "insincere tears", "very angry", "very sad"],
  "answer": "insincere tears"
},
{
  "id": 632,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Please don't talk......the film.",
  "options": ["for", "during", "in", "all of the above"],
  "answer": "during"
},
{
  "id": 633,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "She hung the painting......the table.",
  "options": ["along", "across", "above", "none of these"],
  "answer": "above"
},
{
  "id": 634,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Throw up the sponge.",
  "options": ["to love", "to hate", "to surrender", "to attack"],
  "answer": "to surrender"
},
{
  "id": 635,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "Rank and file.",
  "options": ["punishment", "common man", "high status man", "bald man"],
  "answer": "common man"
},
{
  "id": 636,
  "type": "english",
  "question": "The study of historic or prehistoric cultures is called:",
  "options": ["climatology", "anthropology", "psychology", "archeology"],
  "answer": "archeology"
}






];

export default quiz;